[MUSIC]
[音乐]
>> Stanford University.
斯坦福大学
Welcome to Stanford CS193P, Winter of 2015.
欢迎来到2015年冬季的 CS193P 课程
This is Lecture 9, I believe.
这是第9课
And today, we are going to turn on our clicker here and
我先把遥控器打开
then we are going to.
然后我将展示给你们
I'm going to show you a brief, very brief demo,
一个非常简短的 demo
in addition to the Autolayout Demo that we did last time.
我们上次写的 Autolayout demo
I challenged you in that one to add buttons to
向 Calculator 中添加一些 button
your calculator, then I didn't show you how to do that.
但是我没有告诉你们该怎么实现
So I'm gonna show you how to do that.
所以我会告诉你们怎么做
How, in a different size class,
对于不同的 Size Class
you could add some views that aren't in another size class.
你可以添加不一样的 view
Then we're gonna talk about two big topics today.
接下来我们会探讨两个话题
One of them is ScrollView, okay.
一个是 ScrollView （滚动视图）
And the second one is Multithreading.
另一个是 Multithreading（多线程）
And, kind of as a preamble to do multithreading,
在讲 Multithreading 之前
I'm going to talk a little bit about closures.
我会提及一些 closure 的知识
Now, you should all have read your reading assignment, so
你们应该都完成了阅读任务
you all know about closures.
所以你们都应该了解一些 closure 的知识
But, I just wanna emphasize something about them.
我就是想强调一下这方面的知识
That will start to be more important as we
当我们在多线程里使用 closure 的时候
start using closures more for things like multithreading.
这就变得更重要了
So, let's make a quick little detour here.
让我们快速进行以下的内容
I'm just gonna open up Autolayout here.
我先打开 Autolayout 项目
So here's autolayout.
这就是 Autolayout
And what I wanna be able to do is add another
我想做的事情是
view only in one of my size classes.
只在其中一个 Size Class 添加一个 view
So here's my Any, Any size class.
这是 Any Any Size Class
And let's say I go back to my Any Width,
回到之前我们进行到的
Regular Height that we were working on.
Any Width Regular Height Size Class
And let's say, when we're in this particular arrangement,
在这种特殊的布局下
we wanna have,
我想要
you know, an extra button up here or something.
在这里添加一个按钮之类的东西
And all we need to do that is to drag out whatever
我们需要做的
the extra UI you want is, like this Button.
就是把你需要的 UI 元素拽进来
And if you inspect the button with the Inspector,
在它们的 Inspector 页面
Attributes Inspector.
Attributes Inspector
Down at the very bottom, you'll see, right here,
在最底下，在这里
that there is some switches that control where this
这里有控制这个按钮
button appears.
应该在哪里出现的选项
Now, since I dragged this button into this size class,
我是在当前 Size Class 拖拽进来的
it assumes I only wanted it in this size class.
所以它假定我只想让这个按钮出现在这个 Size Class 里
You see where it says Installed, right here?
看到这个 Installed 被选中了吗
I could put it in all size classes by clicking this.
我可以通过点击这个地方，把它放入所有的 Size Class 中
That means it'll be in all size classes.
这表示所有的 Size Class
Or I could take it out of this size class only,
或者通过点击它
by unclicking this, okay?
我也可以不让它在这个 Size Class 出现
And you can add more things.
你也可以把它添加到更多的 Size Class 中去
I could say in Compact Width,
Compact Width Compact Height
Compact Height, I want this button to be there or not.
我是否希望按钮出现在那里
Okay?
OK?
And that's true for constraints, as well.
这对于约束也是适用的
If you have a certain constraint.
如果对于某个约束
Like we've got constraints down here,
像这里的这个
like this one right here, that are only in this size class.
只在当前 Size Class 里
Because these things are only down here in this size class.
因为它们只出现在当前 Size Class 里
So you can see that's switched.
你可以看到，这是可以转换的
So, whether something is even there and
不管对于 UI 元素还是约束
also the constraints, you can control right here.
你都可以在这里控制
And someone asked me, oh, I did all this work in here, for
有人可能会问
all this size class, but I changed my mind.
我在这个 Size Class 做完了所有工作，但是我改变主意了
I don't want it to be different in that size class.
我不想在这个 Size Class 不一样
How would I go back and undo all this?
我怎么样才能返回呢？
Well, the way you would do
完成这件事的方法就是
that is bring up your document outline.
打开 Document Outline
And you can select all your constraints.
你可以选中所有的约束
You can actually shift > click to select.
也可以按住 shift 进行多选操作
I could select all my constraints.
我可以选择所有的约束
And you can see over here, in the Inspector,
你可以在 Inspector 里看到
it's going to show me that, you know, some of.
它会展示给你这些的信息
It's got a dash here instead of a check.
这里是破折号而不是对勾
So, kind of some of them are there.
类似的东西
And if just go here and say, boom, and remove that.
如果我点击这里移除它
Now, all my constraints are only in my base class.
所有的约束现在只存在于 Any Any Size Class 中
There's no constraints that are just in this one.
在当前 Size Class 里没有约束了
And, in fact, if you look down here.
如果你看这里
Look, all these constraints are all gone.
所有的约束都消失了
So, in fact, if I go here and Update Frames.
如果我点击 Update Frames
Boom, it goes back to the way it was.
它们就回到了本来的位置
You see?
看到了吗
Everyone understand that?
每个人都明白了吧？
So, Constraints and the Views can be turned on and off
Constrains 和 View 可以在 Attributes Inspector
by just inspecting them in the Attributes Inspector, okay?
被调整显示的 Size Class
That's all I wanted to show you there.
这就是我想要展示给你们的
All right, back to the slides.
好的，回到 slides
All right, so let's.
好的
Talk about ScrollView.
接着我们来讨论 ScrollView
All right so, you can see this iPhone right here.
你可以看到这里有一个 iPhone
This is like,
它像 iPhone 1
I don't know, iPhone 1 or something-looking thing.
或者其他的版本
But, I keep it around because it's a really cool example of
我把它放到这里
the power of ScrollView.
是想给你们展现一下 ScrollView 的强大
And what you can do with ScrollView.
你可以对 ScrollView 做些什么
Especially with ScrollViews inside ScrollViews.
尤其是 ScrollView 内部还有 ScrollView
So, watch this little movie here go as we scroll around,
一起来看看这个短片
up and down.
到处滑动
Okay, so that's just normal side-to-side scrolling.
侧面的滑动
But there's up and down within the side to side.
在侧面滑动里面还可以上下滑动
When I get to one, I can go up and down.
我可以上下滑动
And then this app, at the bottom, I can scroll side to
对于这个应用，在底部
side at the bottom and also up and down.
我可以向两边和上下滑动
So, you see how the scrolling can kind of
所以
go both directions.
滑动可以向两个方向进行
Depending on what you've scrolled into view.
取决于你要滑动什么
So, ScrollView is very smart about knowing which
ScrollView 很清楚
way you're scrolling.
你正向哪个方向滑动
And having, you know, opposing ScrollViews and
ScrollView 能够
stuff work properly, okay.
正确地工作
Now, we're not gonna be able to have time, in the brief
我不会占用简短的时间
time we have here, to discuss how to make all that work.
讨论怎么让它工作
But I just want you to know the power is there.
我只想让你知道它的能力
So, someday, if you wanna build an app that has some UI
如果有一天你做的 App 有这些东西
like that, you know where to go, which is ScrollView.
你应该知道，看 ScrollView 的内容
So, we're gonna talk about the basics of ScrollView.
所以我们来看看 ScrollView 的一些基础
Kind of how to get a ScrollView to work.
怎样让 ScrollView 工作
First, let's talk about how we add subviews to
首先，怎样在 UIView 中
a normal UIView.
添加 SubView
So, I got a normal UIView here.
这里有个普通的 UIView
This white view in my iPhone here.
iPhone 中白色的 view
And I wanna add a subview to it.
我想给它添加 SubView
And so, you know, from Lecture 5, I think, that I just create
在 lecture 5 大概，我创建了
the frame which positions it and then I say add subview.
frame 然后 addSubView
Okay, so I've got this view called Logo.
把这个 view 起名为 Logo
And it's just a UIView.
它是一个 UIView
An image view, probably.
也许是个 imageView
And, so I just add subview and, boom, it appears.
我只是 addSubView，它就出现了
Simple as that.
就是这么简单
It's really easy.
很简单
So, what is the analogy to doing this
ScrollView 类似的处理方法
for ScrollView, okay?
是什么？
Let's go look at that.
让我们一起看看
So, in a ScrollView, if you wanna add a subview.
在 ScrollView 中，如果你想添加 SubView
The most important thing you have to do is talk about
需要做的最重要的事情就是
how big the area you wanna scroll over is.
你需要滑动的区域有多大
So, you set this property in ScrollView called contentSize.
在 ScrollView 设置叫做 contentSize 的属性
So, here I'm gonna set my contentSize to 3000
这里我把它设置为 3000 宽
wide and 2000 high.
2000 高
So, I'm gonna scroll over this huge space, okay?
所以我会在这个巨大的区域滑动
Once you set the contentSize,
一旦你设置了 contentSize
now you can add subviews just like you do a normal view.
你就可以像一个普通的 view 一样向它添加 SubView 了
So, here I got logo frame.
这里我获取了 logo 的 frame
I'm gonna set the frame to way over on the left there and
我把它放到右上角
I am going to add its subview.
添加 SubView
So I'm adding that subview to the ScrollView.
向这个 ScrollView 当中
But instead of it appearing onscreen there,
为了让它显示在屏幕上
it's just kind of placed in this content area.
你只需要把它放置到 content 区域就可以了
And so, I could add another one.
我也可以添加另外一个
Here's a huge image, aerial view of Stanford.
这是一个 Stanford 的鸟瞰图
And so, I'm gonna set its frame and
设置它的 frame
add it as a subview, okay.
给它添加为 SubView
So this is the fundamental,
这是最基本的
this is all there is to ScrollView.
ScrollView 的内容
It's really simple, actually.
实际上非常简单
It confuses people for some reason, but
在某些方面，人们对于这个很困惑
it's really just this simple.
不过它就是这么简单
You set the contentSize,
设置好 contentSize
then you add subviews to the ScrollView.
给它添加 SubView
Now, the ScrollView is just going to
ScrollView 就会在那个 content 区域
be a window on that content area.
变成一个 窗口
You see, it's just gonna scroll around,
你可以到处拖动
looking in that content area.
在 content 区域中
And it'll see all the subviews as it
在这个过程中
moves around in there, okay?
可以看到添加的 SubView
So, that's it.
就是这样
That's all there is to it.
就这些
ScrollView is actually incredibly easy to use.
ScrollView 很容易使用
Now, you can reposition the views, anytime you want,
你可以在任何时候重置 view 的位置
just like you could if they were subviews.
如果有 SubView
You can just change their frame and they'll move around.
你可以改变它们的 frame，它们就会到处移动
Or change the logo's frame, move it around.
改变 logo 的 frame，移动它
I can also change the contentSize.
我也可以改变 contentSize
[NOISE] And now it zooms down.
现在它向下移动
I can set the contentSize to be
我可以把 contentSize 设置为
the size of the biggest subview.
最大 SubView 的尺寸
And now, again,
同样地
when I scroll around, it's just zooming around, okay.
当我滑动的时候它也在移动
So it's very common in the ScrollView,
这在 ScrollView 中很常见
obviously, to set its contentSize to be the size of
把 contentSize 设置为
the biggest subview.
最大 SubView 的尺寸
So that it exactly contains it.
刚好能容纳下它
Okay, now, as this thing moves around, you might wanna know,
当它到处移动的时候
where is it, okay?
你想知道现在的位置
What we are currently looking at in my content area?
我们在看 content 区域的什么东西
And you do that with the property in
你可以通过 ScrollView 的
ScrollView called contentOffset.
叫 contenteOffset 的属性获取
And it's simple.
很简单
It's just an x-y offset from the upper left,.
它是一个对于左上角顶点的 x-y 偏移
Of the upper left of the,
ScrollView bounds
you know, bounds of the scroll view.
的左上角
Okay, now what about the actual rectangle
正在显示的
that's showing?
真正的矩形区域
What is that?
是什么
That is actually the scroll view's bounds.
它实际上 ScrollView 的 bounds
Okay, it's very important to understand that that is
理解这一点很重要
just the scroll view bound, that yellow rectangle I'm
我正在给你展示的黄色矩形
showing you there, that's the scroll view's bounds.
是 ScrollView 的 bound
But if you want to know what that rectangle is
如果你想知道在 content 中
in the content, like, in that aerial view,
这个矩形的坐标，在 aerial view 中
what is that rectangle, then you have to convert it.
你可以转换坐标
You have to convert the scrollView's bounds using
使用 convertRect 方法
convertRect, [COUGH] which is UIView method.
是个 UIView 的方法
You have to convert it to that,
你可以把它转换为
to whatever view you wanna convert it
你想要转换的任何 View 的坐标
to like the aerial view whatever that aerial view is.
无论是哪个 aerial view
Does that make sense?
能听懂吗？
So that rectangle is the scroll view's bounds.
这个矩形是 ScrollView 的 bounds
Okay?
OK?
Questions?
有问题吗？
All right. That's easy.
这很简单
So that's it.
就是这样
That's pretty much it to setting up a scroll view and
这基本上就是
knowing where the thing is scrolling.
设置 ScrollView 的一些步骤
Couldn't be simpler actually.
不能再简单了
How do you create a scroll view?
如何创建一个 ScrollView
There's actually numerous ways to do it.
实际上有好几种方法可以实现
You can drag one into your storyboard.
你可以拽一个到 StoryBoard 中
That's what I'm gonna do in the demo.
我在 demo 中也会这么做
You can actually select a UI view in your storyboard and
你也可以在 storyboard 中选中一个 UIView
go up to the menu up there,
在餐单中
and say embed in scroll view, just like we did embed in
embed in scroll view
navigation controller in a previous thing.
就像我们在之前 Embed in Navigation Controller 一样
You can of course create Scroll Views in code.
你可以使用代码创建 ScrollView
They're just views, so
它是 view
you can write a UIScrollView frame whatever.
你可以创建一个 UIScrollView frame 之类的
And boom, you've created a Scroll View.
这样你就创建了一个 ScrollView
So, they're just normal views.
它们只是普通的 view
And then the code if you wanted to
如果你想通过代码添加
add those subviews in code would look exactly kind of
SubView，那么这些代码
like what was on the previous slides.
和之前 slides 的会看起来完全一样
Which is we might create an image view here,
也许创建了一个 imageView
the green is just creating UI image view,
绿色的部分创建了一个 UIImageView
and then I'm just calling addSubview.
然后我调用了 addSubView
But if you just do this, these three lines of code,
如果你只写这三行代码，它不会有效
it won't work because you have to set the content size.
因为你还没有设置好 contentSize
If you don't set the content size,
如果你没有设置 contenSize
it starts out zero, until you bring your Scroll View up,
它以0开始
and they'll be nothing there.
它上面就会什么都没有
Because you won't have that big white area to scroll
因为你不会有那个
around in.
巨大的白色区域来滑动
Okay?
ok
So no matter what Sub Views you add,
不管你添加了什么 SubView
if you don't have that big white area defined,
如果你没有设置 contentSize
then Scroll View will not be showing anything.
ScrollView 就不会显示任何东西
Okay, so it's as simple as that.
就是这么简单
This is a review of what I showed you graphically.
这是对之前的总结
Now you can scroll around.
现在你可以到处滑动
The user scrolls around by just using their finger.
用户通过手指滑动
Right? They pan around.
使用 pan 手势
But you can scroll programmatically too by saying
你也可以通过代码滑动
scrollRectToVisible and this will take a rectangle in the
调用 scrollRectToVisible
content areas view coordinate system, that content size.
content 区域的坐标系统
And it'll scroll the Scroll View to be showing that.
然后使得 ScrollView 滑动到那里展示这个内容
And animated is whether it slides over.
animated 参数是是否滑动过去
If you don't say animated, it's just gonna jump there.
如果为 false，它会直接跳到那里
Which is kind of abrupt to the user, if it's on screen.
这会有些唐突
And there's tons of other things you can do
你也可以做好多别的事情
with a Scroll View that I'm not gonna really talk about.
我不会讲太多
But you can lock the scrolling direction, so
你可以锁定滑动的区域
it'll only scroll up and down, or only scroll left and right.
它只能向左右滑动或上下滑动
It'll flash the scroll indicators if the content size
如果 contentSize 修改了，scroll indicators 会闪一下
has changed.
如果它改变了
You can control that.
你可以控制它
There's a whole bunch of stuff you can look at
你可以在文档中
UIScrollView in the documentation.
看到大量的关于 ScrollView 的东西
Okay?
Ok?
I'm going to have one thing important about
我会介绍 ScrollView 中
scrollview which is zooming.
很重要的一个东西，就是 zooming
Cuz so
到目前为止
far I just showed you kind of moving around and of course in
我给你们展示了怎样到处滑动
scroll you can also zoom in on the content area, okay?
当然 ScrollView 也可以 zoom in
Zooming in requires you to do a few things though.
zoom in 需要你做一些工作
One thing is you have to set the minimum and
其中一件事是
maximum zoom scale.
设置 zoom scale 的最大值和最小值
So the zoom scale is just how much you'll zoom in.
zoom scale 是你 zoom in 的程度
So, if you have a zoom scale of 2.0,
如果设置为2.0
then that means that you'll only zoom to twice the scale.
这表明你只能 zoom 为原来的两倍大小
And if you're 2.5, it'll zoom down to half of whatever
2.5 表示 2.5 倍
the normal size is of the thing you're looking at is.
normal size 是你正在观察的尺寸
So you have to set these.
所以你需要设置这些
If you don't set these they'll be default to 1, and
如果你没有设置这些，那默认是1
it won't work because the scaling will go from 1 to 1.
因为 scale 只能从1到1，所以不会起作用
Okay? And so
OK?
that means not scaling at all.
这表示根本不 scale
The other thing you have to do is use a delegate.
另一件需要做的事时使用 delegate
So here's the second time I've showed you a delegate.
这是我第二次给你们展示使用 delegate
Now I had you do all that work with a calculator to
在 calculator 中
do the delegate so that you'd be
我使用了 delegate
ready to do things in iOS that use delegates.
第一次使用 delegate
And here's one.
这是第二次
'Kay. You've set yourself as
你把自己设置为 ScrollView 的 delegate
the ScrollView's delegate, and you implement this method.
然后你实现它的方法
You have to implement this method if
你需要实现这个方法
you want zooming called viewForZoomingInScrollView.
viewForZoomingInScrollView
So the scroll view when it's zooming, it only zooms in,
当 ScrollView 在 zooming 的时候，它只 zoom in
in the coordinate systems of one of its views.
在它 view 中得坐标系统中
So usually it's kind of the background view.
通常来说它是背景的 view
Like in that aerial example,
就像 aerial 的例子
it would be the aerial view that we would zoom in, okay.
我们 zoom in 的是 aerial view
But we're zooming the whole contents, so
但是我们 zoom 的是整个 content
everything gets zoomed,
全部都会缩放，
but that's gonna be the view that you're zooming in.
但是你需要在一个视图里进行缩放。
So you have to tell it which view that is.
你需要告诉系统这是哪个视图。
It's usually pretty obvious.
通常来说这是显而易见的。
Often times in ScrollView,
通常来说
you're only scrolling on one view anyway but
你只会在一个视图上滚动，但是
you still have to implement this, okay.
你依然需要实现这个方法。
You can zoom programatically once you've set those two
正确的完成这两步后，你就可以使用代码
things up properly.
来进行缩放了。
Then you can set the zoom scale, how zoomed in you are.
你可以设置缩放比例。
It looks kind of like this.
就像这样，
So, here I've got a picture.
这里有一张图片。
Let's say my zoomScale is 1.2.
我的缩放比例是1.2.
I go to zoomScale 1.
现在改成1
I zoom out, zoom back to 1.2 zoomed in.
然后再放大，现在是1.2.
Okay? And same thing with zoom rect.
缩放矩形也是一样的。
So if I had a little rectangle like that yellow area and
如果我有一个黄色区域这样的小矩形。
I said zoom to that rect, it would zoom to make that
然后我要缩放到这个矩形，图片就会缩放
rect fill the edges as much as it could.
到尽可能适应这个矩形。
Or if I have a rect that was really big, and
或者我有一个很大的矩形，
I said zoom it would zoom it down to fit.
图片就会缩小去适应它。
Okay?
So, zoomToRect means make this rect kind of either go big or
所以zoomToRect方法就是提供一个矩形，然后背景放大或
go small to fit.
缩小去适应它。
Okay?
All right?
好的。
There are tons of other delegate methods in
滚动视图有非常多的代理
scroll view.
方法。
One thing, when you start using scroll view,
这里有一个问题，当你开始使用滚动视图的时候，
you're going to ask me is,
你可能会问我，
hey, scroll view has 12 delegate methods.
滚动视图有12个代理方法。
And when I say I implement the UIScrollView delegate
当我要实现滚动视图的代理协议时
protocol, how come the compiler doesn't complain and
为什么编译器没有抱怨说我必须实现
say that it will implement those 12 methods because I
这12个代理方法？我认为如果我说要实现
thought if I said I implemented a protocol,
一个协议，我就要实现协议规定的
I have to implement all those protocols, okay?
所有方法。
The reason that that happens, that you don't get
编译器没有警告的原因是
a warning there is because there is actually, for
因为一些历史原因，
historical reasons, a different kind of protocol,
还有一种其他类型的协议，
which is an Objective-C style protocol.
也就是 Objective-C 的协议。
Objective C was the old language that iOS
Objective-C 是一种老语言，iOS就是用它写成的。
was written in and in the Objective C style protocols
在 Objective-C 的协议里，
some methods in the protocol were allowed to be optional.
一些方法可以是可选的。
Now that's not true in Swift,
Swift不可以这样，
but that's true in Objective C.
但是 Objective-C 可以。
So all these old delegate protocols like
所以像滚动视图代理协议这种老的
scroll view that have optional methods in them,
协议，里边都是有可选方法的。
Swift knows how to bridge them.
Swift 知道如何桥接他们。
You can actually create your own Objective C compatible
事实上你也可以自己写一个 有可选方法的 Objective-C 风格的
protocol with optional methods by saying @objc in front of
协议，只需要在协议声明之前加上
your protocol declaration.
@objc 。
So where you would say protocol face view delegate or
比如你可以写一个 FaceViewDelegate 或者
face view data source you would say
FaceViewDataSource，在声明的时候
@objc space protocol, whatever delegate, and
写@objc 空格 protocol,
then you could put optional in there.
然后你就可以定义可选方法了。
And you can read,
你可以在
this is all covered in the reading assignments, so
阅读材料里读到这些内容，希望
hopefully you've got that.
你们已经都看过了。
But that's the magic that makes it so that when you say
正是因为有这个魔法，所以在你
you implement the UIScrollView delegate protocol and
需要实现滚动视图代理协议的时候，你不需要
you don't yet implement all the 12 methods in there.
实现它里边全部的12个方法。
In fact you only need to implement the ones you
你只需要实现你想实现的方法，
want like view for zooming and scroll view.
比如缩放什么的。
That's why that works.
这就是为什么不会报错。
So anyway there are a bunch of
当然还有很多
other delegate methods in there.
别的代理方法。
For example scrollViewDidEndZooming.
比如 scrollViewDidEndZooming 。
So that will be sent to you when the user pinches and
这个方法会在用户用手指缩放完毕离开屏幕的时候
then they lift their finger up.
被调用。
'Kay? And it'll say oh,
它会知道
the user has finished zooming and
用户现在已经结束缩放，而且也能知道
this is the scale they left it at.
现在的缩放比例。
And you, at that point, might want to redraw your view to
在这个时间点，你可能需要重绘你的视图让它看上去
be less grainy, or something like that.
不那么模糊，或者类似的事儿。
If you do redraw your view at the new scale,
如果你确实要在新的缩放比例重绘视图，
you want to make sure you reset the transform.
那么你需要确保你重置了 transform 。
Okay. This property on
这是一个视图的属性，
view called transform is an Affine transform.
它是一种仿射变换。
Really that's all scroll view is modifying.
当你在滚动视图上滑动手指或者
When you pan around and
所缩放操作的时候，
zoom in, it's just modifying the property transform.
实际上就是在改动这个属性。
So, you can go look at the documentation for transform in
你们可以去看视图里 transform的文档去
view to understand what's going on there.
深入了解一下。
Yeah, it makes scroll view really easy in that it
这使得滚动视图的操作很好理解，因为都是
just is modifying this transform.
在改变这个属性。
All right, so that's scroll view.
好，这就是滚动视图。
So, I have a demo of scroll view.
下边有一个滚动视图的演示。
We're going to learn some other
在做这个演示的时候，我们还会学
things along the way while we're doing that.
一些其他的东西。
Okay, let's do that.
开始
Let's go over here.
这里
We're gonna start from scratch again.
我们从头开始做。
So I'm gonna create a new Xcode project.
建一个新的Xcode项目。
'Kay. It's gonna be Single View.
单视图应用。
Those of you who like to follow along are not gonna be
想跟着做的人今天可能
able to today.
不行了。
Sorry.
不好意思。
Because I'm going to be dragging in a file with some
因为我要直接拖一个有很多URL的文件
URLs in it.
进来。
I'm going to call this thing Cassini.
给项目起名叫cassini。
That's going to be the name of my app.
这个就是我的应用的名字。
And I'm gonna put it where I always put everything.
还放在原来的地方。
All right, I'm not going to be doing anything with the app
跟原来一样，我们不需要改动AppDelegate这个
delegate as usual.
文件。
I'm not going to be doing image assets.
这次也不改动图片库。
I'm not going to do the launch screen.
不改动启动屏幕。
So, here I just have a simple storyboard.
只需要这个简单的 storyboard。
I'm gonna also get rid of
这些关于视图控制器
all this ViewController life cycle here.
生命周期的方法也没用。
I don't need that.
这次不需要。
Get rid of that.
删掉。
And so here, simple storyboard only has this one
现在这个简单的storyboard只有一个叫
view controller here called ViewController.
ViewController的视图控制器。
And I'm not even gonna pay any attention to
而且我也不需要关注这个
this view controller.
视图控制器。
Actually, I'm gonna create a new view controller.
我要建一个新的视图控制器。
I'm gonna drag it out here and this new view controller,
从这拖一个出来，这个新的视图控制器
its only job in life it's going to display an image.
唯一的任务就是显示一个图片。
So I'm going give it the URL of an image, a JPEG file or
我可能会传递给它一个图片的URL，JPEG文件或者别的
whatever, and it's going to display it.
什么东西，反正就是显示图片。
That's going to be its job in life.
这就是它全部的工作。
So I need a new view controller for that.
我需要一个新的视图控制器文件。
So I'm going to call this new view controller.
我要给它起名叫。。。。
All right? I'm going here,
点这，
Cocoa Touch Class, it's a view controller.
Cocoa Touch 类，视图控制器。
I'm gonna call it ImageViewController.
起名叫 ImageViewController 。
Cuz that's what it does, it displays an image.
因为这就是它要干的活，显示一张图片。
Okay? Very, very simple.
非常简单。
I'm gonna put it where all the rest of my stuff goes, there.
把它跟我其他的东西放到一起，这。
All right? So here we go again.
好了，又要来一次，
Again, I'm gonna get rid of my
把所有的视图控制器生命周期
view controller life cycle there.
相关的方法删掉。
We're gonna actually add some of those back,
实际上一会儿可能会加一些方法回来，
cuz part of the reason I'm doing this demo, also,
这也是我们做这个演示的一部分，
is to show you a little bit where and
会给你们演示一些视图控制器生命
why, how we would use a view controller life cycle.
周期的内容。
So, my ImageViewController, one other thing,
还有一个事，
let me make sure in our storyboard here, we got this thing,
我得确认一下在storyboard里，
I'm gonna make sure I change the identity of it
我要把这个视图控制器的类改成
to be an ImageViewController.
ImageViewController
So this is an ImageViewController.
现在是 ImageViewController 了。
This is an easy thing to forget, but do that.
这个事情非常容易忘。
Okay, so what do I need in my ImageViewController.
在我的 ImageViewController 里，
Well, I need a UIImageView.
我需要一个 UIImageView 。
We saw that in the Auto Layout demo.
我们在自动布局的演示里见过了。
It's a just a view, kind of like a UI label for images.
它就是一种视图，一种显示图片的标签。
Obviously if I'm going to have ImageViewController,
显然如果我要做一个显示图片的视图控制器，
I'm going to need one of those.
我肯定需要一个这个东西。
Now, I could just drag it out into my story board, but
我可以从storyboard里拖一个进去，但是
I want to use this demo as an example to show you
我希望通过这个演示给你们看一下如何通过代码
how you create a view in code, create and use a view in code.
来新建一个视图并使用它。
So instead, I'm just gonna have a private var here.
这里我建一个私有变量。
I'm gonna call it imageView.
我叫它 imageView 。
And it's going to be a UIImageView.
类型是 UIImageView。
In fact, I'm just gonna create it right here.
我要在这直接新建。
Okay.
So I have this image view.
现在我又了这个图片视图。
I'm just calling it there.
我在这直接新建了。
Notice, I'm not using the frame.
注意我没用frame新建。
So it's going to create this image view.
所以我这个新的图片视图
It's going to be zero, zero, by zero, zero.
的frame就是
It's going to be, it's framed.
（0,0,0,0)
It's going to be, now it's not in any super view anyways, so
现在它不属于任何视图，
it really doesn't matter what its frame is yet.
所以它的frame 是啥也不重要。
Okay. It's obviously going to
当然，在我们让它显示
matter a lot once we start putting images in there.
图片的时候就很重要了。
I'm also going to create a little private var
这里我还要写一个叫 image 的
here called image.
私有变量。
And this is going to be a computed var.
这是一个计算属性。
I did this in Auto Layout as well.
在自动布局演示里我做过。
It's going to be a UIImage.
它是UIImage类型的。
And all I'm going to to here in the getter,
在 getter 方法里，
I'm just going to return the imageView's image.
我让它返回 imageView.image 。
And in the setter,
在 setter 方法里，
I'm basically just going to set the imageView's image to
我直接就写 imageView.image = newValue.
the new value.
Now, why do I do this?
为什么要这么做？
'Kay, I'm doing this for
我这么做的原因
the exact same reason that I was doing it in the other one,
跟我之前做的完全一样，
which is that when the image is set in my imageView,
我希望我的 imageView 的图片设定好以后，
I want to be able to do things, I want to intervene.
我可以对它做事，我可以干预它。
So I basically I want to kind of be able to do
所以我想要做一些
the did set kind of thing to make that work.
类似于didSet的事情。
So, what's my warning here, UIImage.
啊，这个警告是什么，UIImage 。
Okay, so here we go.
好了。
So in other words right here, when this is set,
换句话说，当这个设置的时候，
when this image gets set.
当这个图片设置的时候。
Setting this image just is going to set the image in
设置这个图片就是设置了imageView的图片，
the imageView, that's all it does.
这是这句代码的意思。
But I can put other code that I
下边我还想加更多的
want down here because I'm going to
代码，因为我希望在我的图片变更的时候
need to do some things every time my image changes.
可以做更多的事情。
I don't care about getting but every time my
我不关心 getter，但是每次图片设置了
image gets set in my imageView I need to do some stuff.
的时候我希望imageView可以做一些事情。
Let me see.
那么
Well, let's talk about what some of those things might be.
让我们看看可以做什么。
For example,
比如，
when I set it I probably want to do imageView.sizeToFit.
当我设置图片的时候，我希望做 imageView.sizeToFit 。
Okay. So when you change the image
当我们改变图片视图里的图片时，
that's in image view, this is kind of like saying label.text
这个就好像是 label.text 等于什么什么。
equals something, right, I'm changing the imageView that,
事实上我是在修改图片视图，
the image that the imageView's showing.
修改它的显示的图片。
When you change it, it does not change the bounds or
但是当我们改这个的时候，不会改变图片视图的bounds
the frames of the image view.
或者frame。
So, sizeToFit causes it to.
sizeToFit 可以。
So ImageView looks at the image, sees how big it is and
图片视图会观察图片，看它有多大，然后根据这个来拓展自己的
expands its frame to fit.
frame去适应它。
So that's clearly something I'm going to do every time I
这个很显然在我每次变更图片的时候希望
change the image I want to do that.
做到的。
So now you can see why I have this nice little convenience.
所以现在你知道我为啥要这么做了。
You can kind of think this is similar to
你可以把它想成setImage
having a function called setImage.
方法。
But it's just nicer to do it as a property cuz then I
但是把它当作属性这样处理更好，我同时有了 getter 和 setter，
get set and get and my code looks really nice.
而且代码更漂亮。
'Kay, so there's that.
这个完事了。
I'm also going to do viewDidLoad, okay?
下边我要实现一下 viewDidLoad 。
So viewDidLoad, we know that we of course need to call
首先，我们当然需要调用super,
super, and what I'm gonna do in viewDidLoad?
我要在 viewDidLoad 里做什么呢？
Well, I'm just gonna add my imageView to
我需要把图片视图加入到
the view hierarchy.
视图的继承树里。
Okay, I'm going to plop it right here.
我要把它放在这。
Again my storyboard, got this thing,
在我的storyboard里，要把这个视图
got my view as a top level view.
作为顶级视图。
I'm just going to add my view in here.
我现在要把图片视图加进来。
Now, I'm not doing a scroll view yet, okay.
到目前，我还没开始做滚动视图。
I'm going to do it without a scroll view, so
我现在要通过不使用滚动视图来实现，然后看看
we can see what that looks like.
是什么样的。
So I'm just gonna say view, addSubView, my ImageView.
我这里写 view.addSubView(ImageView)
Okay, and we know that this is fine to do because
这样做没有问题因为我们知道
viewDidLoad happens after pretty late in the process.
viewDidLoad 会在很晚才回被调用。
Now, I'm not doing anything here that's geometry based.
现在我做的事儿跟尺寸什么的没有关系。
I don't set any frames or anything like that, so this is
我没有设置frame或者别的什么，我就仅仅
just putting the ImageView in there with whatever frame it
把图片视图加了进来，并不管它的frame是多大，
has, either from the last sizeToFit that it got or
不论它从 sizeToFit得到的尺寸还是仍然是0，
it's still zero, zero because it's never been set.
0是因为它还没设置 frame 。
Okay.
So I'm just adding it as a subview there.
我仅仅是加了一个子视图而已。
Now, let's talk about what the model is in this
现在我们还看一下这个视图控制器的
view controller.
model是什么。
What is it's model?
它的model。
Look for the model right at the top here.
咱们把model加在最上边。
It's model is going to be into public.
model应该是公有的。
It's going to be a public resettable model,
应该是公有并且可以重置的，
which is an image URL.
它是图片的URL。
And it's just going to be an NSURL, so an NSURL is a class
类型是 NSURL，NSURL是用来存储 NSURL 的类，
that holds a URL, like http:// some Stanford.edu something
比如类似 http://Stanford.edu 的东西。
and that's going to be the model, and every time we
这就是我们的model，每次设置它的时候，我们就会得到
set the model it's going to get to that image and
它相应的图片然后把
put it in the view, okay?
图片放到视图里。
Everyone understand our nice model here.
大家都明白这个很棒的model了吧。
It's a very,
这是一个非常
this is a very well designed MVC it has a very clear model.
设计的非常好的MVC，有一个非常清晰的model。
It's clear what it does in its view.
model对于视图的作用也非常清晰。
So one thing that whenever our model is set,
只要我们的model设置了，
though, we want to make sure that we update our UI.
我们就希望UI可以确保被更新。
So when our, if we set a new image URL I'm immediately
如果我们设置了一个新的图片URL，我就会把现有的
going to set whatever existing image we have to nil.
图片设置为空。
Because we're changing it,
因为我们要变更图片，
and then I'm going to call a function fetchImage.
然后我要调用一个fetchImage方法。
Okay? And
fetchImage is just going to fetch the image that's in
这个方法会根据URL提取图片，
the URL, and load it up into my image view.
并把图片载入到图片视图里。
So, I need this private function fetchImage, okay?
所以我们需有一个私有方法 fetchImage 。
So let's talk about how we get an image from a URL.
下面我们看看如何从一个URL里提取图片。
If someone give me a URL, how do I get the JPEG image or
如果有人给了我一个URL，我如何才能得到JPEG图片或者
whatever that goes along to it?
里面的其他内容？
And it turned out to be quite simple.
非常简单。
First, I'm gonna make sure that my image URL is not nil.
首先，我要确保这个图片的URL不为空。
If someone asks me to load up nil,
如果有人要求我载入一个空的URL，
I'm not gonna do anything.
我就什么都不做。
So I'm just gonna basically ignore that.
忽略掉它。
So if it's not nil, so my URL is not nil, I'm gonna go and
如果不为空，我的URL不为空，我就要到
go out to the Internet, or if it was a local file,
网上或者本地，因为它也有可能是一个本地
it would be the local file, and get the image data.
文件，去拿到图片的数据。
So I'm gonna say imageData equals, and
这里写 imageData 等于
I can do that with the class NSData.
这里我要用 NSData 类，
And you'll remember NSData from a long-ago lecture,
也许你会记得 NSData 在很久以前的一堂课上讲到过，
maybe lecture three or four.
第三课或者第四课吧。
NSData is just a bag of bits.
NSData 就是一个装比特的包裹。
Right? So I'm gonna reach out on the
所以我现在要到网上
Internet and grab the bag of bits, which is this JPEG file.
把这个包裹抓下来，这个包里就是一个JPEG文件。
And I do that by using contentsOfURL initializer
这里用 contentOfUrl 这个初始化器
here, and I just give it the URL.
然后把URL传递给它。
So I can go out and get that.
然后我就在网上得到数据了。
Now this could return nil.
但是这个是有可能返回空值的。
What if I just gave it some bogus URL, 'kay?
如果我传递了一个假的URL呢？
There's no file there.
里边没有文件。
So let's check and make sure this is nil.
我们需要检查它是否为空。
So I'm gonna say if the imageData does not equal nil.
这里写 if imageData != nil
Why do I keep getting the caps lock there?
我怎么一直开着大写？
I'm not really sure what I'm doing there.
实在不知道我在干嘛。
ImageData does not equal nil,
ImageData 不等于空，
then I can do something about it, else, I can't.
然后我就可以对它做些什么了，如果为空，就不能。
So I could do if let, by the way, here, but
我可以写成 if let，但是我这么写
I'm doing it this way for a reason.
是有原因的。
You'll see a little bit later.
一会儿你就知道了。
So if the imageData's not nil, what am I gonna do?
如果imageData不为空，我要做什么呢？
Well, I need to turn that imageData, that bag of bits,
我要把imageData，装着比特的包裹，
into a UIImage.
转化成一个UIImage对象。
UIImage is the class in iOS that represents an image.
UIImage是iOS里展示图片的类。
So that's really easy to do.
非常容易实现。
I'm just gonna say,
我只需要写，
in fact, I'm just gonna assign it to my image.
我要把它赋予image变量里。
I'm sorry, we don't need self there.
啊，对不起，这里不需要写self。
I would say image equals UIImage with the data
写 UIImage(data: )
being that imageData.
参数是刚才的imageData。
Okay?
Now, otherwise, I'm just gonna say my image equals nil, 'kay?
要不然，我的image就为空。
And, remember, this image equals something like this is
记住我们给image赋值的时候，这里的代码
just calling this right down here to
就会被执行。
set the image in our imageView or whatever, okay?
给我们的图片视图设置一个图片。
And then, of course, this needs to be unwrapped.
当然，data需要解包。
But we know we can unwrap it because I
我们知道这个肯定可以解包，因为我之前
checked to make sure it's not nil.
检查过以确保它不为空。
Okay, now, this line of code is a very bad line of code for
现在我们回头来看，这行代码是非常有问题的
us because it might go out over the network.
因为它会访问网络。
Okay? I could be on cellular.
我可能在用蜂窝网络。
This might take ten seconds, or a minute, or it might just
这个操作可能需要10秒，甚至一分钟，也有可能
fail because I have no network connectivity right now, okay?
因为没有网络连接而直接失败。
So this is not a line of code we wanna be executing in
我们不希望在我们的程序里有这样
our program, but
的代码。
we don't know what to do about it right now and I'm gonna
但是我们现在还不知道怎么做，在这次课的后边我会讲到
show you later in the lecture what we can do about it.
应该怎么做。
So, for now, we just got this kind of bummer line of
现在我们先把这行会让我们程序变得很慢
code here that's gonna be really slow.
的烂代码放在这。
Our app is gonna be really slow.
我们的程序会因为它变的很慢
Although the network at Stanford here is so、
尽管斯坦福大学的网很快所以你可能
fast that it probably won't even seem that slow, but
感觉不到慢，但是
it will be slow cuz I'm gonna grab some pretty huge images.
如果我要下载一些很大的图片，它就会慢下来。
All right, there's one other thing I wanna show here in
下面我可能会给你们看一些关于
terms of view controller life cycle, though, which is,
viewcontroller生命周期的东西。如果
if someone sets my imageURL, okay, and
有人设置了图片的URL。但是
I'm not on screen, do I really want to go and
我们的app不在这个界面上，我是不是需要开始用客户的
start using up their cellular data plan, okay?
蜂窝网络开始下载呢？
Probably not, 'kay?
不应该这样，对吧？
You gotta remember that people don't have Stanford WiFi
人们不可能在哪都能连到
internet everywhere.
斯坦福的wifi。
Some people are using cellular, and it costs money.
很多人在用蜂窝网络，是花钱的。
So I am not going to actually fetch this
所以如果我不在这个界面上的时候，我不希望
image unless I'm currently on screen.
图片开始下载。
So how do I tell if I'm currently on screen?
那我怎么知道是不是在这个界面呢？
Actually I can do that with view.window does not
我可以这么做，view.window != nil
equal nil, 'kay?
So remember view is our top level view in our
view这个属性是我们viewcontroller最顶层的
controller's view ,and .window is the UI window it's in,
视图，它的window属性如果为空，就说明
which will be nil if it's not currently on screen, 'kay?
我们现在不在当前的界面上。
But there's a little bit of a problem here,
但是这里有个小问题，
which is what if I'm offscreen and someone sets my imageURL,
如果我不在这个界面，有人设置了图片的URL。
I don't fetch the image, and then I come on screen?
图片不会开始下载，但是如果我之后回来了呢？
Aah!
Then I gotta fetch the image, 'kay?
那么我就应该开始下载，对吧？
So where does that happen?
那在哪实现这个部分呢？
Anyone wanna hazard a guess where I would put that code?
有人想猜一下我应该把代码放在哪吗？
Nobody?
没有人？
ViewWillAppear, exactly, very good.
ViewWillAppear，没错，非常好。
So in viewWillAppear down here,
在 ViewWillAppear 里，
I'm gonna say super.viewWillAppear.
先要调用 super.ViewWillAppear。
And then I'm just gonna say, if my image is nil,
然后这里我要写，如果我的图片为空，
then fetch the image, 'kay?
那么就开始下载图片。
Now it could be that my image is nil because I
有可能我的图片为空是因为我尝试下载
tried to fetch it and it failed, but
但是失败了，这里就会再试一次，然后
it's just gonna try again and fail, that's okay.
可能又失败了，不过这样没问题。
But, obviously, my image is not nil,
但是显然如果我的图片不为空，
then I don't wanna fetch it again.
我就不会再下载一次了。
That would be wasting their cellular data even more, okay?
这样会浪费用户的蜂窝网络。
So here's a classic example of where we
所以这里是实用 ViewWillAppear 的一个
would use viewWillAppear,
经典例子。
because we know it's worth it to go get that data,
因为我们知道我们马上要看到界面，所以在这个点开始从
because we know we're going to appear onscreen, 'kay?
网络上获取数据是必要的。
Everybody understand that,
大家都懂了吗？
view controller lifecycle coming to life for you?
对viewcontroller的生命周期了解了吗？
Okay?
So that's good. So let's go ahead and run.
很好，我们继续。
So you, actually, let's go ahead and
现在我们要放一个
put a default image in here.
默认的图片。
I actually have some URLs.
实际上我已经有一些URL了。
I'm just gonna drag this DemoURL.swift in here.
我要把 DemoURL.swift 这个文件拖进来。
And all this DemoURL.swift does is it just defines
这个文件只是有一些我们今天这个演示
a bunch of URLs that we're gonna use in our demo today.
用到的URL。
So one of them is Stanford, right here.
其中一个是斯坦福的。
So I'm going to load that up.
我要把它加载进来。
So in my viewDidLoad, I'm gonna say, if my image is nil,
在viewDidLoad里，我要写，如果我的图片为空。
then my imageURL equals my DemoURL.Stanford, 'kay?
那么我图片的URL就等于 DemoURL.Stanford 。
So I'm just gonna,
我在
in viewDidLoad, I'm gonna set my imageURL.
viewDidLoad 里设置了我的URL。
Now, it's not gonna actually load this until it
在视图要出现的时候，图片才会真正
will appear.
开始加载。
That's okay.
But I'm just setting it right here, 'kay?
在这设置。
And I'm not, this is really for testing anyway.
不过这个只是为了测试。
I probably don't even need to do that just cuz we're gonna
我们一会儿在正式开始之前，
remove this code once we start really not testing and
会删了这行代码。
actually working.
So let's go ahead and run this and see what we got.
这里我们运行一下看会发生什么。
Oh, so it's not gonna work.
哦，什么都没有。
Okay, so this comes up, it's blank.
是空白的。
Why is this blank?
为什么是空白的呢？
Well, let's look at our storyboard.
让我们看一下 storyboard 。
Here's the entry point to our storyboard.
这里是 storyboard 的入口。
It's this blank view controller.
它指向一个空的 view controller。
Anyway, we don't want that.
我们不希望这样。
Let's move them over here and have it
把它挪到这，让它从
come into our view controller image view controller here.
我们的图片视图控制器进入。
Oh yeah, there we go, we got Stanford.
Oh yeah，我们看到了斯坦福的图片。
That's very nice, but can't scroll around, 'kay?
非常漂亮，但是不能滚动。
Oops.
I can't zoom, can't turn the pinch, nothing.
不能缩放，不能用手指缩放。
Okay, so I can't see it, 'kay?
什么都不能做。
Can't see anything.
So that's, obviously, we need a scroll view, all right?
显然，我们还需要一个滚动视图。
So, let's go ahead and
我们继续
first of all, actually, what should we do first here?
首先，我们应该先做什么呢？
Let's do, let's enhance our user interface a little bit
我们需要增强一下我们的用户界面
more so we can pick other images.
让我们可以选择更多的图片。
I don't wanna just have this Stanford image, I wanna have
我不希望只能看见斯坦福图片，我希望能看见
some different images that we can look around in.
一些不同的图片。
So I'm gonna go over here and
我们到这里拖一个
drag out a split view controller.
split view controller
Where's that split view?
在哪呢？
Right here.
在这。
So let's drag out this splitViewController.
让我们拽一个 splitViewController 出来。
And, as usual, with the split view controller, I'm going to,
跟以前一样，在这个 splitViewController，我要。。。
when I zoom out a little here, we can look at it.
我先缩小一点就能看见了。
I'm gonna delete a lot of the stuff that came with it here.
我得删掉这些没用的东西。
Keep that one.
留着这个，
We'll delete that.
删掉这个。
I'm gonna have,
我需要
my image view controller is going to be the detail, 'kay?
让我们的图片视图控制器作为细节视图。
So I made the detail.
细节视图。
I'm gonna make my entry point here be my
我要把入口挪到
split view controller.
splitViewController
And I'm gonna have my master be this little one that was in
把之前的那个view controller作为主视图。
here before.
By the way, I just Ctrl+drag there and set this little view
我Ctrl ＋ 拖拽到这个view controller，这是
controller that was there when we first started our app,
我们第一次启动app的时候看见的。
this blank view controller.
这个空的 view controller。
I can set it as the root view controller of
我把它设置成导航控制器的根视图控制器，
the navigation controller with Ctrl+drag and
Ctrl ＋ 拖拽到这，选择
pick root view controller here.
根视图控制器
In your, in the demo and in your thing, we, you probably
在你们自己做的时候，你们应该选
did this in Editor > Embed In > Navigation Controller, but
Editor > Embed In > Navigation Controller
you can also do it with Ctrl+drag, 'kay?
你也可以用 Ctrl ＋ 拖拽.
So now I have a nice UI here.
这里我们有一个非常漂亮的UI。
Comes up, shows my nice image view right there.
运行一下，漂亮的图片视图。
If I go back, here's my master.
点返回，这里是我的主视图。
So now, in this master, I'm gonna put some buttons so
现在，在这个主视图里我要加入一些摁钮，这样我们就可以
we can pick different images to look at instead of
选择其他的图片，就不用一直看着
just looking at that Stanford thing.
斯坦福了。
So let's do that, really easy.
开始，非常容易。
I'm just gonna grab some buttons here.
拖一些摁钮过来。
Let's do this.
Let's make the buttons really big,
我们把摁钮弄的大一些。
maybe like 48 point, okay?
48差不多。
This button bigger.
这个更大。
And let's make three of them.
弄3个摁钮。
'Kay?
One of them is gonna be a picture of
一个代表Cassini卫星的
the Cassini satellite.
图片。
Okay, that was sent out as Saturn.
通过土星运载火箭发射的。
Another one is gonna be a picture of Earth.
另外一个是地球的图片。
Another one is gonna be Saturn.
最后一个是土星。
Okay?
So let's do a little bit of our favorite thing here,
现在我们做一些好玩的事儿，
which is auto layouts.
自动布局。
So put that one right in the middle.
把这个放中间。
Put that one right underneath.
这个放它下面。
This one right on top, 'kay?
这个在最上面。
I'm gonna try and reset to suggested constraints and
现在我要重置建议的约束看看
see how that works.
会发生什么。
That didn't work very good, let's undo.
看上去不怎么样，回退。
I think that's because,
我觉得这是因为，
let me make this thing be its normal size, that's why.
我们先把它弄小一点，我觉得这个就是原因。
There we go.
走你。
'Kay?
Put these back.
放回运来的位置，
Hopefully, this will, there we go,
希望这次能行，
Reset to Suggested Constraints.
重置建议的约束。
Oh, still didn't work.
哦，还是不行。
Okay, well, we'll fix them up, manually.
好吧，我们来手动修复一下吧。
So this guy, right here.
这个，在这，
oh, that's so bad, it's not even close.
哦，糟糕，完全不对
Okay. So
I'm just going to do this all manually here,
所以我们完全手动吧。
going to uh-huh, sorry, wrong thing there.
啊，对不起，弄错了，
Okay, Ctrl+drag, let's make it center vertically.
Ctrl ＋ 拖拽，垂直居中。
Let's Ctrl+drag and center horizontally as well.
水平居中。
Let's make this be vertical spacing.
这个的垂直距离。
We'll make this one be vertical spacing we'll have
和它的垂直距离，这里让它们有一样的
these things share their center x, center x.
x中心。
I think we're good to go there.
我觉得这样可以了，
Yep, frames.
对，frame的警告。
So, let's update our frames, less time.
更新一下frame。
Okay, there we go.
好了，这下对了。
All right, so we've got some nice auto layout there, and so
现在也有了很棒的自动布局，
now all we need to do is to segue when these are pressed.
现在我们需要做的就是设置segue，通过点击响应。
We're gonna segue to our Image View Controller down here.
segue到下边的图片视图控制器。
So let's set that up and just Ctrl+drag.
Ctrl ＋ 拖拽连起来。
nope, Ctrl+drag, all right.
不对，Ctrl ＋ 拖拽，对了。
So I'm gonna show detail because in
选择show detail因为
the split view I want it to show up on the detail side and
在split view我希望它显示在细节视图上，在iphone上
on iPhone it's gonna push,.
就是push。
So there's that one, let's go ahead and set its segue.
我们继续，设置它
So this one I'll just call it Earth, 'kay, this one,
就叫它 Earth 吧
down here, show detail we'll call this one Cassini, and
再弄一个show detail，我叫它 Cassini
with this one, show detail, we'll call that one Saturn.、
最后一个，叫Saturn
Okay, so there we go, we've got a nice story board here,
ok了，我们现在有了个漂亮的 storyboard。
we've got these segues all set up in here all
我们设置好了全部的segue，现在要做的是
we need to do is prepare for these segues.
准备他们。
This View Controller right here, okay,
打开view controller。
I'm going to select on this and go here to see its code.
我点这就能看见它的代码。
So here's the code for that View Controller.
这就是view controller的代码。
It's just this blank one that got created when we
这就是我们建立app的时候那个空白
created our app.
的文件。
Okay, and all I need in this ViewController is
我要在这实现 prepareForSegue 。
prepareForSegue, nothing more, so I'm gonna prepareForSegue.
仅此而已，实现 prepareForSegue 。
Actually I'm going to make
我得把它弄的宽
this quite a bit wider here with these huge fonts.
一点，字体太大了。
And in here I'm going to see if it's a segue to
现在我要检查它是不是要segue到我的
an image ViewController.
图片视图控制器。
So I'm gonna say if I can let image view controller equal my
这里写if let ivc =
segue's destinationViewController as
segue.destinationViewController as
an ImageViewController.
ImageViewController
Okay, so we know we're segueing into
现在我们可以确定是segue到
an image view controller.
图片视图控制器。
Then if I can let the identifier equal
然后if let identifier 等于
the segue's identifier, so the identifier's not null,
segue.identifier，这样确保identifier不为空，
then I'm gonna switch on the identifier.
然后对 identifier 作 switch.
This code should all look very familiar to you,
你们应该很熟悉这个了。
and then in case of Earth, 'kay,
然后，如果是 Earth。
we are going to have to set the image URL, 'kay?
我们就要设置图片的URL。
So ivc is an image view controller,
ivc就是我们的图片视图控制器。
its public settable model is the imageURL.
它的公有的可设置的model就是 imageURL。
So I'm gonna set that to DemoURL.NASA.Earth.
我把它设置成 DemoURL.NASA.Earth 。
'Kay, I have a nice one ready to go there.
这个做好了。
I'm also gonna set the title of that to Earth,
我还要把它的标题设置成 Earth ，
'kay, and then same thing here for Saturn.
下边是Saturn，一样的。
It's image view controllers,
这个是图片视图控制器。
imageURL equals the DemoURL.NASA.Saturn.
imageURL 等于 DemoURL.NASA.Saturn 。
ivc.title equals Saturn, and same thing for Cassini.
ivc.title 是 Saturn，下面是Cassini 。
Let's see.
'Kay, and otherwise we will just break, and
最后如果都不是，就break。什么也
do nothing, okay?
不做。
Everybody understand this code?
这些代码大家都能看懂吧？
Hopefully it's completely familiar to you.
希望你们已经非常熟悉了。
Nothing special there at all.
没什么特别的。
Okay, so I think that should work.
我觉得应该没问题了。
Let's try it.
试试看。
Hopefully it didn't clean anything.
希望没弄坏什么东西。
All right, so we go back, we've got these things.
我们点返回，看到这些摁钮。
Let's go ahead, oh,
继续，
my auto layout doesn't look very good there.
啊，自动布局貌似不怎么好。
Probably messed that up, but anyway, close enough.
可能是弄乱了，不过也差不多了。
Let's go Earth, oh, it didn't work, okay?
点 Earth， 啊，不行。
That's because we have back here,
这是因为，我们回到这，
here in our image controller, we have this test code here.
因为在我们的图片视图控制器，有一些测试代码。
Let's get rid of that, right there.
把测试代码删掉。
Try again.
再试一下。
Right back now, let's look at Earth, and
试试 Earth
look how slow this this, you see what I'm talking about?
非常慢，看到没？
Like, hello,
hi
can't do anything, can't click on any buttons.
啥也干不了，也点不了别的摁钮。
Finally, we get this and this does not look like
最后我们看到了图片，貌似不是地球，
the Earth to me, looks like a bunch of dim photos.
像是一些很暗的照片。
I don't know what that is how about Cassini?
不知道这是些什么，那Cassini呢？
oh, we got the outer space part of Cassini right, but
啊，我们看到了外太空的部分，
that's all we can see because we need the scroll view now.
但是也只有这些了，我们需要滚动视图。
We absolutely have to have the scroll view.
必须要用滚动视图了，
These are big images so we can not see anything without it.
如果没有，这些很大的图片，我们什么也看不见。
So let's go back and put our scroll view in here.
咱们回来，加上滚动视图。
All right, so how are we gonna put the scroll view in here?
怎么加入滚动视图呢？
Well, I'm actually gonna put the scroll view in
我要用 storyboard 来加入
using the storyboard.
滚动视图。
So, I'm gonna drag a scroll view in.
拖一个滚动视图进来。
That's kinda a simple way to do it.
应该是比较简单的方法了。
So, let's bounce out here so
缩小一点，
now we're back to our Image View Controller.
来到图片视图控制器。
All right, this is our Image View Controller, and
在这，我要拖
I'm just going to drag out a scroll view.
一个滚动视图进来。
I'm gonna search for
在这里搜索，
it, scroll, there it is, drag it out here.
scroll，啊，在这，拖进来。
I'm gonna place it so that it's right on the edges with
这样放，沿着蓝线，这样
the blue lines right there.
就跟边缘对齐了。
I'm definitely gonna do Reset to Suggested Constraints.
肯定也是需要重置建议的约束。
I'm gonna make sure that works, which it did,
检查一下是不是成功，行了。
'kay, no magic numbers.
没有魔法数字。
Everything looks nice right there, and now I
看上去没问题了，
just need to put my image view inside this scroll view right.
现在我需要把我的图片视图放到滚动视图里。
So I got this scroll view here all I wanna do is put
我要做的就是这个，把图片视图放到滚动视图
the image view inside of it.
的里边。
So how am I gonna put that imageView inside of it.
我要怎么做呢？
That's very, very, very simple I'm just going to
非常非常简单。我只需要给滚动视图一个
create an outlet to this thing.
outlet。
Let's put the outlet right here.
把outlet放在这。
Okay, I'm going to call the outlet scroll view, and
起名叫scrollView，
as soon as that outlet is set
设置好了。
in it's did Set I'm going to simply say to.
在didSet里我们要做，
The scroll, well actually, we, you know,
实际上我们已经加上了
we already added the scroll view.
滚动视图。
Let me make this a little easier on you.
我们做的简单一点。
See right down here where we add the image view to
看到这里图片视图已经加到
our view?
我们的视图？
Instead, I'm just gonna add it to the scroll view, 'kay?
相反，我只是把它添加到滚动视图中
So you can build your view hierarchy in view did load.
这样你可以在 viewDidLoad 中建立视图层次关系
It's actually a pretty good place to build it,
这里实际上是个很好的地方来创建它
cuz all your outlets are set, so we know this is set, and so
因为你的所有 outlets 都设置好了，我们知道这个已经设置好了
we can build our view hierarchy here, 'kay?
我们可以在这里建立我们的视图层次
So I just added the subview to there but I do actually need
我刚才已在那里添加了子视图，但实际上我
this didset here.
需要在这里调用 didset
I need again to make this wider so
我需要再次把这个变宽
you can see it because when I set my scroll view what's
这样你们可以看到，因为当我设置我的滚动视图时，
the most important thing to make a scroll view work?
让一个滚动视图工作最重要的事情是什么？
The content size, right.
contentSize，对吧
So when my scroll view gets set,
因此当我的滚动视图被设置了
I need to set the content size, so
我需要设置 contentSize
I'm gonna say scrollView.contentSize, and
所以我要设置 scrollView.contentSize
what size do I want it to be?
我需要设置怎样的大小？
Well I want the content size to be exactly the same size as
好吧，我需要 contentSize 和 imageView
the image view, so
的大小一致
I'm just gonna say imageView.frame.size.
我要设 imageView.frame.size
'Kay, now that's not, oops, equals.
这不是，等于
That's not the only place I need to do this, though, 'kay?
这里不是我需要做这个操作的唯一地方
Any time my image changes,
任何时候我的图片改变了
obviously my image view might change,
显然我的图片视图也可能改变
I need to change the content size of my scroll view.
我需要改变滚动视图的内容大小
So also here.
这里也需要
Inside the setter for image I need to set my scrollView's
在 setter 里面，我需要设置滚动视图的
content size equal to the imageView's frame size.
contentSize 等于图片视图的大小
Here I'm going to do something kind of interesting,
这里我要做些有趣的事情
which I actually did in auto layout demo after the fact
这是在我发布代码之后在自动布局
when I posted the code, but
例子中做的
I'm going to put a question mark right here.
但我要在这里放个问号
And the reason I'm gonna do that, it allows me to set my
我这样做的原因，我可以在内部设置
image internally, even if my outlets have not been set yet.
图片，即使我的 outlets 还没被设置。
I know that these outlets are implicitly wrapped optionals,
我知道这些 outlets 都是可选的
and of course that means that you can access them,
当然这意味着你可以访问它们
but the reality is you need to protect against the cases
但事实是你在这些变量可为
where those things might me nil.
nil 的情况下做些保护措施
Like setting your image,
比如设置你的图片
somehow, before that was your set.
某种方式，在你设置前
So, now I don't need to do it here,
现在这里我不需要了
because I'm in viewDidLoad.
因为我在 viewDidLoad
And I don't need to do it here because, of course,
我不需要在这里做这些，当然
it just got set.
它已经被设置了
But here, I'm going to do it just to be safe.
但这里，为了安全我需要做这个
Everyone understand that?
每个人都理解了吗？
Okay.
So, let's see.
让我们看看
It should work.
它应该可以工作
All right here we go, let's go try Cassini.
我们从这里，让我试试 Cassini
Slow, okay.
很慢
Oh yeah, look, oh stars.
看看，星星
Oh, what's that?
这是什么？
Oh, look at that.
看这个
Oh, sorry.
抱歉
There it is.
在这里
Oh, oh,.
It's a spacecraft of some sort.
这是某种太空船
Hard to tell, kay?
很难说清楚
We don't really get to see a lot of it, but
我实际上没看到它的大部分
[INAUDIBLE] Cassini.
Cassini
Okay, well obviously we need zooming, kay?
显然我们需要缩放
Because I can't see really what's going on here.
因为我不能看清楚这里所发生的
All right, so let's go back and add zooming.
让我回去，然后添加 zooming
Again, very straightforward.
非常简单
Remember, there's only two things you really need to do.
记住，实际上你只需要做两件事情
You gotta set that min max, and
你要设置 min 和 max
you gotta implement that delegate method.
然后你要实现代理方法
Great place to set delegate methods, of course,
这里是实现代理方法的好地方，当然
is in the setter of outlets.
在 outlets 的 setter 中
If you wanna set the delegate of an outlet, so
如果你想设置一个 outlet 的代理
I'm gonna set the scrollView's delegate to be myself.
我将设置滚动视图的代理为我自己
Of course I'm gonna have to say that I implemented.
当然我必须实现（代理）
That's the problem here.
这是问题所在
Okay.
We'll do that in a second.
我们一会就做这个
While I'm here I'm going to set the minimum zoom scale
这里，我将设置 minimumZoomScale
to 0.03.
为 0.03
This is a very,
这是张非常
very large image that we'll be able to look at here.
非常大的图片，我们可以在这里看到
And the maximum zoom scale to 1.0 and
然后 maximumZoomScale 为 1.0
maybe these don't wanna be magic numbers.
可能它们不想为神奇的数字
Maybe these want to based on the actual size of
可能它们想要根据图片视图的
the imageView.
实际大小
Okay?
So you might want to make it so
所以你可能想要让它
that you can perfectly zoom out to fit the scrollView or
完全缩小以适合滚动视图或
something like that.
其他类似的视图
But I'm just picking numbers here to
但我挑这些数字只是为了
make this code simpler.
让代码简单
So let's go fix the fact about the delegate here.
让我们修改下这里的代理
So I'm just going to go up here and say,
我要到这上面来，我要设置
oh yes, ImageViewController is a UIScrollView delegate.
ImageViewController 为滚动视图的代理
And, as soon as I say that,
一旦我设置了
this warning went away down here, but
这下面的警告就没了
I didn't get a new one that said, oh,
我没有另一个新的（警告）
you don't implement this.
你没有实现这个
And again, cuz this is the old objective C
因为这是老式的 objective C
style protocol where there's optional methods.
风格的协议，这是可选方法
So, I'm going to implement one of
我要实现它们中的一个
them though which is view for zooming in scrollView.
即 viewForZoomingInScrollView
Okay, as soon as I typed viewFor,
只要我输入 viewFor
it knew what I was talking about.
它知道我想输入什么
And I'm just going to return my imageView because that is
我只要回到图片视图，因为
the view that's inside the scrollView's content area that
它在滚动视图的内容区域中
I want to zoom on.
就是我想放大的
And that's it.
这就是了
That's all we need to do, so let's go run.
这就是所有我们需要做的，让我们运行下
Now we should be able to go and
现在我们应该能够
take a look at Cassini in all of its grandeur.
看到 Cassini 的全部华丽壮美
I'm just going to hold down Option so that I can pinch.
我要按住 Option 键，这样我可以捏（图片）
And I'm just pinching in here.
我在这里捏
Oh there it is. And let's go ahead and
这就是，让我们继续
rotate the other way.
旋转到其他方式
There we go.
我们看到了
So we can see it and zoom out a little bit.
因此我们可以看到它缩小了一点点
We can still scroll in addition to zooming.
我们依然可以在缩放的时候滚动
Okay? And let's go look at
让我们看看
this Earth thing so
这个 Earth 图片
we can figure out what the heck is going on with that.
现在我们总算清楚它在干什么了
So slow.
这么慢
Okay, so here it is.
这就是了
Oh, now we can move around and look at things.
让我们移动开，看看
Let's zoom in on this a little.
让我们在这里缩小一点
[INAUDIBLE] oh, whoa, it's the Earth.
它是地球
Woo, okay.
So, yes and as we can imagine, guess what this one is.
既然我们可以想象，猜猜这个是什么
Pictures of people.
很多人的照片
So this is actually made up of composites of images of
所以这个实际上是人们向 Cassini 挥手的
people waving at Cassini.
照片拼图
Kay they're taking pictures of themselves waving, see?
他们在挥手的时候拍的照片
Hello Cassini.
你好，Cassini
So that's what this composite is made of and
这就是这张拼图的内容
then I'll push in that Saturn out of there.
我要推动土星离开那里
'Kay so.
NASA, pretty cool.
NASA，相当酷
All right.
Okay, so that's good.
这很好
So that's all I'm gonna show for now.
这是我现在想演示的所有内容了
We'll get back and work on the fact that our app is really,
我们一会将返回，然后解决我们 app 相当相当慢的
really slow in a minute.
问题
Gotta show you some stuff first though.
先给你们看些材料
'Kay, any questions about that?
关于这个有问题吗
ScrollView's really easy to use, but you just
滚动视图很容易掌握，但你们
gotta know these particular things like the delegate and
要知道这些特别的东西，比如代理和
that min max zoom scale and that content size.
minmaxZoomScale 以及 contentSize
As long as you do those things,
只要你们做了这些事情
it'll work really great.
它就能工作的相当好了
All right, so a little aside here.
先把这些放一边
Just a two minute aside.
只是放一两分钟
I'm gonna rip through these slides about closures, but
我要讲讲这些幻灯片上的闭包
there's an important aspect about closure that
这是关于闭包非常重要的方面
you need to know.
你们需要知道
Kay?
Closures, when you have a closure in your code,
闭包，但你们的代码中有闭包时
it captures any variables that are used inside
它会捕获闭包中使用的任何外部变量
the closure from the outer scope, where the thing is,
这个是
which is a really cool feature.
是非常酷的特点
That's what makes it a closure really, okay.
这实际上也让它成为了一个闭包
Is that it captures them, okay.
闭包是这样捕获它们
You can make incredibly elegant code out of
你可以使用闭包写出难以置信的
this, okay.
优雅代码
Now here's where I'm going to
现在我要向你们演示
show you something about the calculator that if you
计算器的一些东西，如果你们
didn't do this in your assignment, that's good.
在你们的作业没做这个，没关系
Because in your assignment I wanted you to
因为在你们的作业中，我希望你们
use delegation, okay.
使用代理
However, sometimes closures can be a substitute or
然而，有时候闭包可以作为一种替代或者
a better tool to use than delegation.
是个比代理更好的工具
Lets look at this code right here.
看这里的代码
Lets say I have a class called grapher.
我有一个类叫做 grapher
I'm not going to say what kind of thing it could be
我不打算讲这是什么样的东西
because some of you haven't turned in your homework yet,
因为你们中有些还没把作业交上来
but lets say I had a grapher, okay.
但我有一个 grapher
And it doesn't have a delegate method or anything it just has
它没有代理方法或其他方法，它只有
a var called yForX whose type is a function.
一个变量叫做 yForX，它的类型是函数
A function that takes an x and returns a double.
这个函数有个参数 x，并返回 double
Okay?
Now that's an optional function.
这是个可选函数
That's fine, doesn't have to be set in this grapher.
这很好，在 grapher 中不一定需要设置这个函数
And then what if I just said,
然后如果我
well I'm going to let the grapher equal a new grapher.
让 grapher 等于一个新的 grapher 会怎样？
I'm going to let variable graphing brain be
我将让变量 graphingBrain 等于
a calculator brain instance I just created.
我刚刚创建的 CalculatorBrain 实例
Then I'm gonna set the program of the graphingBrain I
然后我设置我刚刚创建的 graphingBrain
just created to some other program that I wanna graph.
的程序为另一个我想要做图表的程序
Then I'm just gonna say yForX equals a closure and
然后我只要让 yForX 等于一个闭包
inside the closure it just says,
然后在闭包内部，只要
set the variable value to the argument to the closure and
将变量的值传递给闭包的参数
then return the graphingBrain at evaluate.
然后返回 graphingBrain.evaluate()
So do you see how by using this,
通过这个你们就知道怎么使用闭包
first of all we have grapher is completely generic.
首先，我们有一个完全普遍的 grapher
Knows nothing about a calculator brain.
对于 CalculatorBrain 一无所知
And yet we have this five line,
然后我有这五行
six lines of code to implement our graphing and
六行代码来实现我们的制图
it's all incredibly easy to kind of parse what's going on.
这一切都非常容易解析发生了什么
Now this works because the closure,
这个能起作用是因为闭包
that little thing in the curly braces,
即在大括号里的小东西
captured the little graphing brain that I created.
捕获了我创建的小 graphingBrain
Okay, so that every time disclosure is called,
因此每次闭包被调用
every time, you know, grapher one to yForX.
每次，你们知道的，grapher 一个给 yForX
It keeps reusing this graphing brain over and over and over.
它一直保持重复使用这个 graphingBrain
Which is exactly what I want because this
这正是我想要的，因为这个
graphing brain's got the right program in it.
graphingBrain 在它里面获得了正确的程序
It just keeps calling it over and over.
它只是保持不断调用它
It doesn't create a new one every time, it just keeps
它并不是每次都创建一个新的，它只是
reusing it because it captured it from the outer scope.
重复使用它（graphingBrain），因为它从外部范围捕获了它
Everyone understand what I mean by capture?
每个人都理解我所说的捕获了吗？
Now, this is really cool and really elegant,
这相当酷，相当优雅
it looks really awesome, it is awesome, but
看起来棒极了，太棒了，但
there are some dangers.
有些危险
Okay?
Capture danger.
捕获危险
The problem is, if a closure captures a pointer to
问题是，如果一个闭包捕获了一个指向某个东西的
something and that something has a pointer back to
指针，而这个东西有个指针指回
the closure, now you have a loop.
闭包，这样你们就有了一个环
A memory cycle that's going to keep them both in
一个内存周期，这将导致它们永远被
memory forever.
保留在内存中
Okay? Kind of
像
like the memory cycle we were talking about before.
我之前讲过的内存周期
This is easy to have happen in a closure.
这在闭包内很容易发生
This is what it looks like, so
它就像这样
here's another example here of closures.
这里是另一个闭包的例子
I've got this class called Foo.
我们称这个类为 Foo
It's got one property which is a function called action.
它有一个叫做 action 的函数属性
It's got another function called show,
它有另一个函数叫做 show
which takes an integer and shows it, prints it.
这个函数接收一个整型输入，然后输出它
And then it's got a method called setupMyAction, and
然后它有个方法叫做 setupMyAction
setupMyAction has a local variable, x,
setupMyAction 有个本地变量，x
which is an integer.
x 是个整型
That it assigns that action.
它分配了那个 action
[COUGH].
Function, property to a closure.
函数，一个闭包属性
Inside that closure it uses the x.
它在闭包里面使用了 x
That's cool, it captures x.
这很酷，它捕获了 x
This will actually work.
这将能工作
This will print 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
这将输出 1，2，3，4，5，6，7，8，9，10
You can see the doMyAction10times at
你可以看到下面的 doMyAction10times
the bottom.
函数
If you set up my action it will do it because the x
如果你调用 setupMyAction()，它可行，因为
gets captured by the closure and
x 已被闭包捕获，然后
every time the closure get executed.
每次闭包都被执行
[COUGH]. It increments that x and
它递增 x
counts to 10.
然后累计到 10
It's also cool because it's capturing self.
捕获本身也很酷
Because I'm using myself to show the number,
因为我使用我自己来显示这个数字
by calling self.show.
通过调用 self.show
But here's where the danger comes in.
但这也是危险的来源
Okay?
Because self has a pointer to the closure and
因为 self 有个指针指向闭包，然后
the closure inside has a pointer back to self.
闭包内部有个指针指回 self
Now, when you write a closure you'll notice that any
当你们写一个闭包时，你将注意到任何
time you call methods it makes you put self,
时候你调用方法，它都要你输入 self
makes you say self dot.
让你输入 self.
That's because it wants you to be clear.
这是因为它要让你清楚知道
You are capturing self when you call show.
在你调用 show 时，你正在捕获你自己
Okay?
Now, this is a problem, this class
这是一个问题，这个 Foo
Foo and this closure are pointed to each other, they
类，和这个闭包互相指向对方，它们
will stay in memory forever, they can never be released.
将永远保存在内存中，它们永远不会被释放
How do we fix that problem?
我们如何修复这个问题
Well, we can actually say,
实际上我们可以
when we make a closure, do not capture this variable in here.
当我们创建一个闭包时，别在这里捕获这个变量
Okay?
You do that by saying, [COUGH] unowned,
你通过使用 unowned 来实现
whatever the variables you don't want to be captured.
不管变量是什么，你都不想捕获
Okay? You just put it right at
你必须把它放在
the beginning of the closure, before the in.
闭包的最开始，在 in 之前
Okay? If you have arguments,
如果你有参数
you put it right before the, in, there.
你把它放在 in 前面，这里
That will make it work.
这样它就能工作
You can also say weak self.
你也可以使用 weak self
Which is a little different.
这个有点不同
That will make the self be a weak pointer in there.
这将使得 self 为一个弱指针
We learned about weak pointers in the lecture when we
在我们讲代理时我们学习了
talked about delegation.
弱指针
So weak would work, too.
所以 weak 也可行
It wouldn't do it.
它不能够
The difference between unowned is that pointer doesn't have
无主引用和弱引用的区别是，指针若不是一个
to be an optional that can be set to nil.
可选型，那么它可以被设置为 nil
It can just be anything.
它可以是任何东西
You just guarantee that self will never become nil.
你只要保证 self 永远不会变成 nil
So, for the lifetime of this closure,
因此，在这个闭包的生命周期
self can never become nil.
self 永远不会变成 nil
Okay?
Now, self can be released from the heap,
现在，self 能够在堆中被释放
which will release the closure now, from the heap.
这将从堆中释放闭包
That's great, but
非常棒，但
that closure can never be executed while self,
在 self，即 Fool 为 nil 时，闭包将
this Foo thing, is nil.
永不被执行
Which is fine, because it's only used inside Foo,
很好，因为他只在 Foo 内部使用
[COUGH] That would never happen.
这永远不会发生
Okay?
Unowned self.
无主 self
This is all covered in the documentation that you
这全都可以在文档中查阅，你们
were supposed to have read, but, you might have
应该读过了，但，你们可能
not really understood this, or glossed over it, so I'm
没真正理解它，或忽略了它，因此我
just revisiting it to tell you that [COUGH] It's important.
只是重新审视它，告诉你们这很重要
Okay. Because we're going to
因为我们将在这门课程中
start using closures more and
越来越多地使用闭包
more in this class and you will be capturing values and
你们将捕获变量
some of them will point back to the closure.
有些会指回closure
Okay?
[COUGH] Okay, that's it.
就是这样
Next is multithreading.
下一个是multithreading
Okay. Yes, question.
是的，有问题
Is there an example, could you give
例如，能不能举一个
an example other than self where it would point back?
除了它自己可指回的例子？
I think about that swift reference document has a whole
我想Swift参考文档里面有一个大的
big, long example, so I would just refer you to that.
完整的例子，所以我觉得你应该回去看那个
Any other questions about that?
还有其他关于那个的问题吗
[COUGH] Okay.
Okay
Multithreading, how many people in here have done some
Multithreading，这里有多少人
programming in a multithreaded environment before?
之前在多线程环境下编过程的？
More than half, that's more than usual, so that's good.
超过一半，比一般情况多，很好
All right, then this will all be pretty easy for
好的，这对你们来说
you to understand.
非常好理解
Those of you who haven't, it will be a struggle.
这对没有过多线程编程经历的同学可能稍微有些难
The first time you do it, I'm sure all of you can attest,
你们第一次做这个，你们可以作证
it's a little bit harder to understand what's going on.
你们理解这个可能会有些困难
It's actually fairly simple.
这实际上相当简单
What's going on here is, in iOS there are multiple queues.
这里发生的是，在iOS里有多重队列
A queue meaning like a queue at
一个队列表示像是一个在
the movie where people lined up to go see a movie.
电影院人们排着队去看一部电影
A queue in a computer science sense is just a list of things
一个队列在计算机科学里就像是一个
where things go into the front of the queue, go into the back
东西可以进入队列前面或者后面
of the queue rather and they get pulled off the front.
或者被拉到队列最前面
It's a queue of functions, basically closures usually.
这就是一个函数队列，基础的closures
Okay.
Okay
That are sitting there waiting to run.
就坐在那等着运行
Each of these queues has it's own threads to run
每一个队列都有一个自己的线程去运行这些队列
these queues, to process the things on the queues.
去处理队列里的东西
That makes this a multithreaded environment.
这就造就多线程环境
Now, there's a very,
这里有个非常非常重要的
very important queue called the main queue.
队列叫做主队列
This main queue is a serial queue, meaning it
主队列是个串行队列
pulls these functions off the queue one at a time.
这说明主队列一次从队列里拉出一个函数
It never runs [COUGH] Two of them at the same time.
它从来不会同一时间一次运行两个函数
Okay. They're serial, one at a time.
是连续的，一次一个
And all UI activity has to happen on the main queue.
所有的UI活动都必须发生在主队列
So if you ever wanted to have a function or closure,
所以当你想要一个函数或是closure
that is executing some code, that did anything with the UI,
这就会执行某些代码，这就会做任何关于UI的事
you have to put it on the main queue.
你必须把他放在主队列
It can only execute on the main queue.
这只能在主队列里执行
This is how basically the UI is protected
这就是UI是如何被从被混入多线程的环境中
from getting messed up in the multithreaded environment.
被根本上保护的
It has this main queue.
它获得了主队列
Okay? So the main queue,
所以主队列
very, very important.
非常非常重要
The main queue never wants to
主队列绝对不想
be doing anything that might block NS data contents of URL.
做任何可能阻塞包含URL的NSData的
That should never be in the main queue.
所以这绝对不要出现在主队列里
So we're going to have to get that off the main queue.
所以我们要把那个从主队列中拿出来
All the code that you write normally in
所以你通常写在你的
your MVC that's all happening on the main queue.
MVC里的代码都发生在主队列里
View did load, view will appear, all that stuff,
View did load, view will appear，所以东西
all happening on the main queue automatically for you,
所有都为你自动的在主队列里发生了
you don't have to do anything special.
不用特地去做什么
Okay?
But, there are other queues that iOS will create for you
但是iOS还会在你需要的时候为你创建其他队列
as you need, and we're going to show you how those work.
我会给你们展示这些是如何做到的
First of all, how do execute a function or
首先，如何在另外一个队列里
a closure on another queue?
执行一个函数或是closure？
Well, you do that with this function [COUGH] Called,
你用这个函数来做到
dispatch_async.
叫做dispatch_async
Okay?
So you say dispatch_async, the argument,
所以就有dispatch_async 参数
there's two arguments, a queue and a closure.
这有两个参数，一个队列一个closure
The first argument is the queue.
第一个参数是队列
I'm using the trailing closure syntax here to
我在这用了trailing closure语法
put the closure outside the parentheses there but
来把closure放到了括号外面
you just specify what queue you want to
但你只要指明你想用哪个队列
execute the closure on and then you pass it to closure.
来执行closure，然后你再传递closure
Okay? And the closure takes no
Okay?closure没有参数
arguments, returns no arguments and that's it.
不返回参数，就是这样
That's how you do it.
这就是你的做法
Couldn't be easier.
不能再简单
dispatch_async on the queue you want.
dispatch_async就在你想要的队列上了
So how do you get the queue that you want?
那么你怎么获得你想要的队列呢？
Well, you get the main queue using this function
你可以通过这个函数获取主队列：
dispatch_get_main_queue and that returns the main queue.
dispatch_get_main_queue，然后就能返回主队列
There's also an object-oriented way to do it,
也有个面向对象的方式去做到
NSOperationQueue.mainQueue.
You got this queue and
你获得这个队列
here's an example of putting something on the main
这有个把一些东西放进
queue dispatch_async, [COUGH] notTheMainQueue,
主队列的例子dispatch_async （notTheMainQueue）
something, and then inside there [COUGH] You could
在这个里面
say dispatch_async_main_queue.
你可以说dispatch_async_main_queue
This is how you do multithreading programming.
这就是你如何做到多线程编程
Those lines of code right there.
这些代码在这
I want to do something that doesn't block the UI, so
我想做一些不阻塞UI的事
I dispatch it to notTheMainQueue,
我就把他发送进notTheMainQueue
some other queue,
一些其他的队列
[COUGH] I'll talk about how to get those queues in a second.
我一会会说道如何获取那些队列
Then I do it, go do something like NSdata contents of URL,
然后我做一些像是包含URL的NSData
blocks, whatever.
blocks之类的
When it's done, I need to talk back to the main queue to
当这做完的时候，我要再说回主队列
update my UI with the image I got or something like that.
用图片或者类似的东西来更新我的UI
The way I do that is [COUGH]
我做这些的方法是
I dispatch back to the main queue.
我发送回主队列
So you nest these calls to the dispatch.
所以你把那些调用都发送回去
Okay?
You're basically running code on another queue and when
你只是把代码运行在另外一个队列里
it wants to dock back to the main queue it just posts or
当他想对接进主队列的时候他只是
puts some code back on the main queue.
发送或者放了些代码回到主队列
Now, the main queue might be busy.
现在，主队列可能正在处理一些事情
But when it's done it's a serial queue but
但当这做完的时候，这是个串行队列
eventually it will get to this block and it will run it.
但最后还是会获取这个block并继续运行
Okay?
Everybody understand that?
所有人都懂了吗
That's it.
就是这样
It's so simple really, actually when you see it,
这真的很简单，事实上当年看的时候
it's almost too simple.
这真的好简单
The code, when you write it, it's so simple you
你在写这些代码的时候，因为太简单了
can get confused and forget that you're in a multithreaded
你甚至会忘记你是在多线程环境里
environment, but this is really, those lines of
但这真的是多线程
code you're seeing right there at the bottom, that is
你看到的底下的这些代码
the fundamental multithreaded programming syntax in iOS.
这就是iOS中最基础大多线程编程语句
How do you get these other queues,
怎么获得其他队列，
you don't want to run on the main queue.
你不想在主队列中运行的
You get a queue from the system by asking for
你通过向系统申请一个恰当档次的service
a certain quality of service.
来获取队列
And the four qualities of service,
有四个档次的service
there's user interactive,
这是user interactive
which is I'm going to do something off the main queue,
表示我将要在主队列外做一些事情
but the user really wants this done fast, and
但用户想非常快的处理它
it's not going to take very long.
不能耽误太久
So do it right now.
所以现在就做
Okay? So it's a high
Okay?所以这是个
priority queue for things that go really fast.
高优先级的队列来让事情处理的很快
Then there's USER_INITIATED which is the user just
下一个是USER_INITIATED，是一个
asked for this, but I know it's going to take a long time
用户请求这个，但我知道这要很长时间
fetching an image off the network,
去从网络抓取图片
we would USER_INITIATED, but it's still pretty important.
我就会用USER_INITIATED，但这也很重要
Then there's utility, which is I'm just doing something.
下一个是utility，是我只是做一些事情
The user didn't just ask me to do this.
用户没有让我去做
But it's just something I
但我只是
need to do in the background processing things or whatever.
需要做一些后台进程之类的事
But it is something that matters right now to the user.
但这是一些现在就关系到用户的事
So it would be nice if it returned somewhat soon, but
如果现在就能返回一些东西那就最好了
it's not like got to have it.
但不会去主动获取这个
And then there's background which is like things that
下一个是background
are not concerned with what the user is doing right now.
像是一个不关心用户现在在做什么的事
Like oh I'm pre-fetching some data, updating some database,
比如我正在预抓取一些数据，更新数据库
cleaning up a database, doing stuff in the background.
清楚数据库，在后台做一些事
It really has nothing to do with the user doing now,
这真的跟用户现在做的事没关系
you understand what I mean?
你理解我的意思吗
Just background task.
只是后台任务
So you create a quality of service,
所以你建立一种级别的service
you do that with this really odd int.
你用一个奇怪的int去做
One of these constants above there,
上面的其中一个常数
.value, close parentheses, okay.
.value，闭括弧
For historical reasons, they have them put a nice,
因为历史原因，他们在swift里有个很好看
new UI in there Swift, which is interesting.
的新UI，很有趣
But anyway, you do that.
不管怎样，你就是做了这个
And then you just say,
然后
queue equals dispatch_get_global_queue with
that quality of service, comma 0.
That comma 0 is reserved for future use, okay?
那个0留着以后会用到
And that's it.
就是这样
Now you have another queue.
现在你有了另外一个队列
You can now dispatch async to it, and
你现在可以dispatch async给它
be running code off the main queue.
并且在主队列外运行代码
Simple as that.
就是这么简单
You can create your own serial queues too.
你可以建立自己的串行队列
I'm not going to talk about that really, but
我不准备讲那个
you might have something where these queues that I'm
但你可能会在我上面提到的
talking about at the top,
几种service中
these quality service based ones, are concurrent.
同时用到
So actually a single queue, like the user interactive
所以一个单独的队列，像是user interactive队列
queue, could actually have multiple threads running,
可以真的多线程运行
working on it at the same time.
同时在上面工作
If you have a multi-core processor they can
如果你有个多核处理器
even actually be working on them.
它可以真的在上面工作
But mostly it's time sharing,
但大多数情况是分时的
time slicing between the various threads.
时间分给了数个线程
But, anyway, you can do a serial 1.
但是你可以做一个serial 1
And you would do that only if you wanted to do something off
只有当你想在主队列外
the main thread that something depends on the next things,
做一些事的时候，这些事根据下面的事区分
depends on the next things.
根据下面的事区分
So you want to want to do them serially or
所以你想连续的去做
you want to throttle.
或者你想可控速度的去做
Like you're fetching a bunch of images, but
比如你想要抓去一些图片
you don't want to bombard, you know,
但你又不想让他们占了全部网速
Flicker or whoever you're requesting the images from
Flicker或者任何你想用上百个问题
with hundreds of questions.
来请求图片的网站
You're just going to do them one at a time.
你只想一次做一个
And they're going to appear in the UI one at a time.
任何他们就会一次在UI上显示一个
So you can do your own
所以你用dispatch_queue_create
serial queues with dispatch_queue_create.
自己做一个串行队列了
Okay?
You can also use the multi-threading stuff to
你以后也可以
do something in the future.
用多线程去做一些事
Okay? You do that with
你通过
this dispatch after.
稍后发送这个做到
It's kind of odd again.
这又有点奇怪了
The arguments are kind of weird, you do this Int 64
参数有些奇怪，Int 64
delay in seconds times double insect per min insect per
delayInSeconds*Double...
milliseconds dispatch time now delay, blah blah.
...(念语句)
You create this basically time dispatched_time t
你只是最基本的
that is in the future and then you just say
用dispatched_time创建了队列
dispatch after that amount of time on to the main queue.
在之后的一段时间会发送到主队列
So you're almost always doing dispatch after on
所以你差不多经常要
the main queue.
稍后发送到主队列
It's rare that you'd be on another queue
你在别的队列做这个真的很罕见
because those other queues are kind of
因为另外一个队列
concurrent running queues and such.
事同时发生在运行队列的
Anyway it's more likely, I want to put up an alert in
这更像如果用户十秒钟什么都不做
ten seconds if the user hasn't done something, or
我就显示一个警告
something like that.
或者类似的
Which is kind of a weird UI, but anyway.
是一种奇怪的UI
You never want to block the main queue saying oh wait,
你绝对不要想阻塞主队列，说：嘿，等下
20 seconds and then it will be able to do this.
20秒，然后就可以做这个了
But you want to be able to notify it.
但是为了提示这个
And there's tons and
并且有很多
tons of stuff that I'm not even going to talk about, but
很多的东西我还没讲到
you can do readers and writers.
你可以做readers 和 writers
You can protect critical sections of
你可以保护你代码的
your code doing this.
关键部分去做这个
You can do synchronous dispatch.
你可以做synchronous dispatch
Okay, instead of asynchronously firing these
代替异步去执行
things off to put on the queues.
这个队列
You can wait for them to execute.
你可以等待他们去执行
All that stuff.
所以的东西
You won't need any of that for this class probably.
你可能不需要他们中的任何一项
The things I showed you, that's the basics of it.
我给你们看的，是最基础的
That's probably all you're going to need.
这可能就是你们需要的全部
'Kay?
Okay？
There are APIs in iOS that are multi-threaded.
这在iOS中的API是multi-threaded
So, you've got to be careful.
所以你要小心
If you're doing something, and
如果你做了什么
it seems like this might be multi-threaded,
可能会是多线程的
this seems like it might take a little while,
这就表示可能要一会功夫
like it's gonna access the network or
可能要获取网络
something like that.
一类的事情
Then you want to read the documentation and
任何你就要读文档
see, are you giving it a block, for
看是否让他阻塞了
example, that's going to be executed off the main thread?
比如，是不是要执行完主现场了？
Because in that block, if you want to do something with
因为在这个阻塞里，如果你想要做一些UI的事
the UI you have to post back to the main thread.
你需要发送会主线程
Okay? So here's what
Okay?所以这就是
that looks like for example.
例子看起来的样子
Here is an API, this is the NSURL session API.
这有个API，这个NSURL session API
The thing in yellow is all that really matters.
黄字非常重要
It lets you download a file from a URL.
它让你从一个URL中下载一个文件
And it does it asynchronously.
而且是异步的去做
And you give it a block, which is the completion handler.
你用completion handler给它一个block
So when it's done, it invokes your block,
当它做完了，它会唤醒你的block
and it's got some arguments there.
并且这会获取一些参数
It moves the file to a local URL that you can open.
这会移动文件到一个你可以打开的本地URL
You get HTTP response, you can get an error, et cetera.
你获取HTTP应答，你看你会得到一个error或者别的什么
So, you want to do something in there to update the UI,
所以，你想要在这做一些事来更新UI
cause you got the file back, and can you?
因为你取回了文件，那么你可以吗？
No, you can't, because that's not on the main queue,
不，你不可以，因为那个不在主队列里
however you can put dispatch async in there.
但你可以放一个dispatch async在这
Okay, so this is exactly the same code,
所以是完全一样的代码
I just add dispatch async in there.
我只是在这加了dispatch async
All right?
So that's example where you dispatch a.
这就是你在哪放dispatch async的例子
That is the exactly the same thing as I showed you on that
这就是我刚才在第一张课件给你们看的东西
very first slide, it's just that it's wrapped inside an
只是包含了一个iOS API
iOS API instead of just your own dispatch to another queue.
而不是发送到另外一个队列
Okay.
All right so.
所以
Again, a demo's worth of vowels and words.
一个值得仔细说的例子
So let's go look what it looks to make an Imaginarium there.
所以来看看看如何做一个Imaginarium
Or Christini I guess I called it this time.
这次我猜我叫他Christini
Let's make this thing be multi-threaded.
来把它变成多线程
So we know that it's really bad UI, it blocks every
我们知道这是个糟糕大UI，每次我们请求大图片
time we ask for these big images, it's completely stuck.
都会阻塞，真的很不好
So where we fetch the image right here,
所以我们在哪获取图片呢？
we need to be doing that on a different thread.
我们要在另外一个线程里做
All right? So how are we
All right?
going to do that?
所以我准备做这个
We'll we're going to do exactly what I
我们就是要做
did in the slides there.
之前课件里讲的
Which is I'm going to create one of these quality of
我要在这建立一个之前说的
service things here, okay.
service中的一个
First of all, I don't need to do
首先，我如果image URL为空
anything if my image URL is nil.
我什么都不要做
So if it's not nil though,
如果不是
then I'm going to let my quality of service equal,
如何就让qos等于
let's go ahead and do this so you can see lots of code here.
继续，你可以看到很多代码
All right,
All right
I'm gonna select this quality of service to this weird thing
我要选这些service中的一个
int and the quality of service I want is going to be this
有些奇怪的service
user initiated because the user has asked for something.
我想要这个user initiated，用户请求一些东西
It's not gonna be quick,
这不会很快
but I want it to be done as soon as it can.
当要经快的完成
Because the user's waiting for it basically.
因为用户在等着
So that's gonna be my quality of service there.
这就是我要的service
And then I'm just going to say dispatch, async.
然后就是dispatch async
The queue I want is a global queue, so
我要的是一个global queue
I'm going to say get global queue.
获取一个global queue
I'm gonna actually use a different one of these,
我要用一个完全不一样的
hold on.
等等
Identifier global queue.
Identifier global queue
And use this one,
用这个
which is the one that takes the quality of service there.
一个要选service的
So quality of service.
quality of service
Not caps, Q O S, there we go.
qos，好了
The flags are always zero there, and here's my block.
这里的 flags 参数总是 0，这里是 block
All right?
看到了吗？
So let's double-click to do that.
让我们双击这个 block
I'm going to put that outside, you know,
把它放到括号的外部
the trailing closure syntax here I'm going to use.
我将会使用的是尾随闭包语法
Now inside here, now I can do the things that slow.
在这个 block 内部，我可以处理一些较慢的工作
So, let's put all of this inside here, to start.
把下面的这些都放进来
Even though we know that's not going to be good.
即使这可能不太正确
All right?
好
So, I dispatched async in here.
在这里 dispatch_async
Notice that it's already complaining that you gotta put
注意 Xcode 已经发现了错误
self in here.
你需要在这里加上 self
That's because I put this inside of a closure.
这是因为我把它放入一个闭包内部
And it's capturing self because I'm accessing my
因为我尝试获取 imageBar
image bar here.
所以它捕获到了 self
All right, so I can fix that one.
我把它改正过来
Let's go ahead and do that here as well.
这个也一样
Extra parenthesis.
多余的括号
Okay, so that's good.
这看起来还不错
Now, this is fine,
很好
this is that thing that's going to be slow.
这种很慢的工作
It's happening on another thread right now,
我们已经把它放到另一个线程处理了
that's great.
这很棒
But this is not great because here, this is going to
但是也有些问题
cause UI stuff to happen all over the place, right?
这里会涉及 UI 的元素
Look at all this UI stuff it's going to do.
看到了吗？这里的 UI 元素
So I cannot do this on this thread.
我不能在这个线程处理它们
So I just have to dispatch it back to the main thread.
所以我需要把它们放回到主线程运行
The main two actually, and
实际上是主线程的队列
again I'm going to use the trailing closure syntax there.
在这里我还会使用尾随闭包的语法
That's exactly why they designed it that way.
这就是为什么他们会这样设计线程
All right, so
好
now I'm dispatching back to the main queue.
我已经把它们放回了主队列
That's good and all is well.
一切都很好
And that's it.
就是这样
That's all it took.
这些就是需要进行的工作
So you can see the multi-threaded, it's like,
在一系列工作之后，你可以到多线程是什么样了
after you've made it, except for this weird end thing.
除了这些奇怪的 Int 操作
It made about the minimal amount of codes you could
它可以让你进行有可能
possibly be.
最少量的编程工作
All right, this is not quite right,
不过还是有点问题
we're not quite done here, but
这里还是没有完成
let's go see if this has fixed our problem at least.
让我们一起看看，这是否至少已经修复了之前的问题
So here we are, so I'm going to go Earth.
选择 Earth
Now look, I can go back.
看到没？我可以返回了
My UI is completely active.
UI 是时刻相应的
I can do anything I want,
我可以做任何想做的工作
even though it's still loading that thing in the background.
即使程序仍在后台载入图片
And eventually, once it's kind of sucked it all down,
一旦最终完成了载入
it shows it to me, and I can zoom in on it.
它就会展示给我，我可以缩放它
Here we go.
就是这样
Okay, so that's exactly what we want.
这就是我们想要的效果
And it took virtually no code on our part.
事实上我们没写多少代码
However, it's not quite right.
然而，还是有点问题
And if you have experienced multi-threading, you're gonna
如果你曾经了解过多线程
immediately understand what I'm talking about here.
你会立刻明白我接下来将要叙述的内容
This is kind of lulls you into thinking,
这有点哄骗你的意思
oh I got this right okay ready to go next problem.
这我已经做好了，我可以处理下一个问题了
But what happens if this image data takes a long time to
但是如果花费很长时间下载图片数据的时候
come back and in the mean time the user asks for
用户请求了一张新的图片
a different image.
会出现什么问题？
Well, we argue, I can't do that of course because we
这里可能会有些争论
segue to and from so we are always creating new nvc but
这不会发生的，因为每次 segue 的时候都创建了一个新的 MVC
imagine a new nvc that stayed on screen.
但是想象一个出现在屏幕上的新 MVC
And there was a way to click a button and
有一个按钮
it would load a new image.
点击它就会载入一张新的图片
Well, this thing might come back after the next request
在下次请求之后，这种情况就可能发生了
and show the user the old image they wanted instead of
程序就会展现给用户上一次请求的图片
the new one they'd asked for.
而不是他们希望的新图片
Do you see the problem?
能想清楚这个问题吗？
So, this is where modern
这里的多线程问题就
threading gets a little hard on your brain.
比较难以理解
It's like, oh, what?
就好像，什么？
These things are happening in a different order
这些发生的顺序都不一样
because they're happening in different threads,
因为它们发生在不同的线程中
different threads of execution here.
不同的线程在执行
So how do we fix that?
我们怎么能修复这个问题呢？
It's actually fairly simple to fix.
实际上非常简单
When this image data comes back, okay,
当这个图片数据请求完成以后
we're just gonna check and see if the URL that caused it
我们验证一下引发图片请求的 URL
to be fetched is the one we currently want.
是不是我们当前想要的
So I'm just going to go here and say, if the url, which is
这里我会这样，if url
this url right here, which was captured by this, okay?
也就是这里的 url
So if this url up here equals self.imageURL, in other words,
验证一下上面的 url 是否等于 self.imageURL
the url that my user currently wants,.
换句话说，是不是用户当前想要的
Then I'm going to do this.
是的话，就这样做
Otherwise I'm going to
否则
completely ignore this response.
我会完全忽视这次回应
Okay, this JPG file came back but the user has moved on.
JPG 文件下载完成，但是用户已经不需要了
They don't even care about this.
用户已经不在乎下载好的图片了
So you see what I'm talking about, where you've got to
这里我叙述的关于多线程内容
think a little bit with this multithreader.
你们应该多思考一些
You can't just throw the code in there and
你不能写完代码往这一放
go, oh yeah, it works.
哦，它起作用了，就不管了
You have to think about things might be happening,
你应该思考一些可能将要发生的事情
taking a long time, cuz they're happening separately.
思考地久一点，因为它们不是同一时刻发生的
So that's good.
还不错
There's really nothing to show there because our UI doesn't
这里没什么好展示的
really allow us to specify a different image.
因为 UI 不许我们列举一个不同的图片
When we click back and forth in our UI,
当我们在 UI 中后退或者前进
we're creating a new MVC every time because we're segue.
会创建新的 MVC，因为我们是通过 segue 连接的
So the new MVC is obviously got its own environment.
所以新的 MVC 有它自己的环境
So the last thing I want to show you is our UI is not
最后一点我想要展示给你们的是
very good because it has a lot of blank white screen in it.
UI 看起来不太好，因为屏幕上有太多空白的地方
Okay, right here, blank white screen, it's like oh,
在这里，空白的屏幕
blank white screen, what's going on?
用户会说，空白的屏幕？发生了社么？
Mm, I don't know, what's happening here?
我不知道这里发生了什么
I don't know.
我不知道
You see what I mean, it's like
你们应该懂我什么意思
I can't even tell what's really going on in my UI.
我不能分辨 UI 到底发生了什么
It'd be nice if when I clicked here I
如果我点击这里
got like a spinning wheel that would say I'm working on it.
出现一个旋转的圆圈，告诉我正在处理，就会好很多
I'm trying to get that thing, okay.
我正在获取图片
So we want a nice little spinning wheel in here.
所以在这里我们需要一个旋转的圆圈
So how do we do the spinning wheel?
我们怎样实现呢？
Spinning wheel, very easy to do.
很容易实现
We're going to go to our story board right here.
选择 storyboard
Screen realty management is a challenge on
在这么小的屏幕上展示这么多内容
this small screen.
很有挑战
And I'm just going to drag out a little spinning wheel
我直接向 UI 中
into my UI.
拖入一个旋转的圆圈
And this is a great chance for me to
向你们展示一下 Document Outline 如何使用
show you a little bit of how to use the document outline.
这里是个很好的机会
And you'll see why.
你们会知道原因的
So here the spinning wheel is called the activity indicator.
旋转的圆圈在这里被称为 Activity Indicator View
So I'm going to type activity, there it is.
在这里输入 activity
Little spinning wheel, drag it out, and going to put it here.
从这里拖出这个小圆圈，放到这里
Now when I drag that out, it kind of looks like okay good,
放置完毕后，UI 看起来还不错
works, got a spinning wheel on there, I'm ready to go.
这里有了一个小圆圈，已经可以开始接下来的工作了
But actually,
但是实际上
something very bad happened when I dragged that out.
拖拽完毕后，发生了很不好的事情
And if I look in the document line, I'll see what it is.
在 Document Outline 你就会发现
Which is that this spinning wheel
这个小圆圈被添加成了
was added as a SubView of the ScrollView.
ScrollView 的 SubView（子视图）
Because I dragged it out on top of the ScrollView, so
因为我把它放到了 ScrollView 的上面
it added it as a SubView so
所以它被添加成了 SubView
that mean it's going to be in that content area.
这就表示它会出现在 ScrollView 的区域
We don't want that, we want this thing to be floating on
我们不希望这样，我们希望它
top of the scroll view.
漂浮在 ScrollView 的顶部
It's very hard to fix it in here.
在这里很难修复这个问题
Cuz it's like where do you drag it?
你能把它拽到哪里去？
The scroll view's everywhere.
这里到处都是 ScrollView
You can't get it.
你不能获取到它
So this is what the document outline is great for.
然而这就是 Document Outline 擅长的地方了
Watch this.
仔细看
I'll take this right out of the scroll view.
我把它拽出 ScrollView
Boom, it's out.
它已经出去了
Now this puts it behind the scroll view,
现在它被放到了 ScrollView 的下面
because I told you the subview's list,
因为我告诉过你们这个 SubView 列表
the top things are in the back.
列表最上面的元素是在 UI 最底层的
So I'll just put the scroll view on top.
所以我把 ScrollView 放到列表最上面
So now I have the scroll view in the back,
现在 ScrollView 已经在 UI 最下面了
indicator in the front.
小圆圈在前面了
Okay?
OK？
What about constraints?
约束怎么解决？
Oh, the constraints here are hard to put too,
这里的约束也很难设置
because every time you kind of drag,
因为每一次你拖拽的时候
it keeps dragging it to the scroll view.
它总被拽到 ScrollView 里
Well, I can do constraints in here as well.
我也可以在这里处理约束问题
Let's drag the indicator view up to
把小圆圈拽到
the view above the scroll view.
ScrollView 上面的 view
Right, our NVC's view.
MVC 的 view
And I'm just going to say I want this to be centered
我希望它在这个 view 的
horizontally and vertically in that view.
垂直中央和水平中央
Boom, I've set the constraints now for
目前我已经通过 Document Outline
that totally using the document outline.
设置好了它的约束
Now lets do one other thing with the indicator.
再对这个小圆圈做一些其他事情
I'm going to inspect it over here and
在这里对其属性进行检查
you can see the indicator has some different styles.
这个小圆圈有不同的风格
We like grey because we
我们喜欢灰色的
have a white background so that's good.
因为是白颜色的背景
But it also has a couple buttons here and
这里也有几个选项
this is a good one to click, hides when stopped.
hides when stopped 这项不错，可以选中
That makes it so
这会使得这个小圆圈
when the spinner stops spinning it hides itself.
在停止旋转的时候，会把自己给隐藏
So it's only showing while it's spinning,
它只会在旋转的时候才会显示
which is kind of a nice feature.
这是一个很好地特性
You can cause it to show and
你可以让它显示或隐藏
hide yourself, but it's nice to have it hide itself.
但是让它自己隐藏还是很不错的
All right, so we have this nice little spinner here, so
我们已经有了这个不错的小圆圈
let's go ahead and hook it up into our UI.
把它和我们的代码联系起来
And I'm just gonna Ctrl+Drag, even control dragging from
按住 Ctrl 拖动
this can be a bit of a pain, because it's very small and
可能从这里拖动比较困难
you got all these constraints in the way.
因为它很小，周围还有约束
So you can actually Ctrl+Drag from over here.
你可以从这里 Ctrl+Drag
All right so I'll Ctrl+Drag, I'll put it right here.
把它放到这里
I'm gonna call it spinner.
起名为 spinner
I like to call my activity indicators spinners but
我喜欢把 Activity Indicator 称为 spinner
you could call it activity indicator too.
但是你也可以不像我这么叫
So here's my spinner and
这就是 spinner
what do I need to do with this spinner?
我应该怎么处理它呢？
Well, I just need to
我只需要
start it spinning when I make a request, and then I
在请求的时候让它开始旋转
need to stop it from spinning when the request is fulfilled.
当请求已经完成的时候让它停止
Okay?
OK？
So I'm going to do that.
我会这么做
And I want to get lots of room here.
我需要一些空间
So I've got my spinner, well, where do I make a request?
我在哪里做的请求的？
Let's see, it's right here.
在这里
Right. This is where I dispatch
这里就是我投递请求的地方
request so I'm just gonna say spinner, start animating.
在这里，spinner.startAnimating
But I'm gonna make that even better,
我会处理地更好
I'm gonna say question mark,
在这里加一个问号
in case we're fetching an image before our
以防在 Outline 设置好之前
outlets are loaded.
发出了获取图片的请求
For some reason, we don't currently do that cause we
我们通常不会这样做
only do it in view will appear.
只会在 viewWillAppear 里这样处理
But you know some day someone might write that code.
但是可能某人某天就会写出那样的代码
And then I could stop the spinner like down in here but
我可以在下面这里让 spinner 停止旋转
actually a great place to stop the spinner is as soon
实际上让 spinner 停止旋转的很好的地方
as an image is set.
是在 image 被设置好了的时候
Anytime an image gets set I don't want to be spinning,
每一次 image 被设置好了以后，我不希望 spinner 旋转
by definition.
显然
Right?
好的
So I'm just going to say spinner.stop animating.
spinner.stopAnimating
Okay?
OK?
And that's it.
就是这样
That's all it takes to the do the spinner.
处理 spinner 就需要这些工作
So let's go take a look at the spinner spinning.
让我们看看 spinner 旋转的样子
All right so the spinner didn't spin at
一开始 spinner 并没有旋转
start because I haven't made any requests.
因为我还没有发出任何请求
But here if I make a request there's the spinner spinning,
但是如果我做出请求，spinner 就开始旋转了
and yeah you can make the spinner larger if you want but
你也可以让 spinner 大一些
it's spinning, it's spinning cuz we're still working on
它一直在旋转，因为它正在处理请求
it and once the thing appears now my spinner's gone.
一旦我需要的东西出现了，spinner 就消失了
It's kinda hard to tell in the dark spots but here in
在暗的区域很难看出来
the light spots you can see that our spinner is gone.
但是在亮的地方你可以看到它消失了
'Kay same thing we come back, click on this one,
我们回过头再做一次，点击它
spinner comes back, right?
spinner 又出现了
And I can't scroll it.
我不能滚动它
There's no scrolling or anything like that.
这里还没有 ScrollView
And then once our thing appears right here,
一旦图片出现
our spinner is gone.
spinner 就消失了
Okay?
OK?
So that's it for today.
这就是今天的内容了
Questions?
有问题吗？
What about the self referencing and.
self 引用的问题
Yeah so let's look at the self referencing thing.
让我们来看看 self 引用的问题
Did we have a problem with
闭包内部
self referencing inside this closure.
有 self 引用的问题吗？
That we did right here, and the answer is no,
答案是，没有问题
because nowhere inside this closure do we refer to
因为我们没有让闭包内部的任何一个地方
anything that points to this closure.
指向这个闭包
Cause this closure just got dispatched a synced,
因为这个闭包刚刚 dispatch_async
right it got put on some queue somewhere, but
被放入了某个队列之中
we don't point to it anymore.
但是我们不再指向它了
The queue points to it basically,
实际上是那个队列指向它
the queue owns this closure, we self don't.
那个队列拥有它，而我们没有
So we're okay, we don't have to do any unknown.
所以我们不需要处理，加上 unknown
But you'll start seeing the unknown thing when we
但是在学习 animation（动画）的时候
start doing animation.
你就会开始看到 unknown 了
When we start having actions in the animation that
当我们开始学习动画
are calling methods inside of our class to do animation, so
在 action 中调用类中的方法的时候
you'll see that there.
我们会看到的
Okay? That's it, thank you.
懂了吗？就是这样，谢谢
For more, please visit us at Stanford.edu.
想了解更多信息，请登录 Stanford.edu